<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gods Will on Ryan Clarke</title>
    <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/tags/gods-will/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gods Will on Ryan Clarke</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2017 Ryan Clarke</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//www.ryanclarke.net/tags/gods-will/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>This is My Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/this-is-my-thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/this-is-my-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been blessed with a good life. Throughout my journey, God has never ceased to shower all manner of sweet providence along my way. Many good things have happened to me that I have had no control over, from the dynamic family I was placed in to the amazing resilience of my fearfully made person.  And then, in love, God gently and surely called me to be His own and bought me with his blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My God has lead my steps, even when I was not consciously aware of His work. At other times when I cried for guidance and direction as I anxiously awaited looming deadlines and decisions, He has never failed to reveal His perfect and often unexpected will even if it may appear to be only at the last minute. Because of this long history of faithfulness to me, I can confidently approach the future with peace that it is in His hands. My present state of uncertainty has only worked to make me more excited about the possibilities ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My new adventure started on Monday, November the 12ᵗʰ.  I had just arrived home the weekend before from a week of work in Vancouver, BC, Canada manufacturing the last batch of MannaFlax with the supplies at our Surrey warehouse, and then packaging all the equipment and machinery for shipment back to Payson so we setup and continue operation in the states. This trip was very significant since it marked the end of the development cycle on the new health supplement we were making as we entered the production and commercial phase and started to sell product. I went to work on Monday expecting to start an endless (and hopefully increasing) cycle of making and selling. Instead, God had other plans. The Payson plant manager came to me and said that due to my efficient work effort in helping create MannaFlax and also some unrelated company financial difficulties I had worked myself out of a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expected to feel hurt or sad or disappointed, instead I felt happy and excited. When I started this job 17 months ago, I did it because God was clearly in it. Though I loved the job, and the interesting work, and fun coworkers, I always realized that the remote location was a very big drawback. Many times during my stay in Payson I’ve wanted to move so I could be closer to family and friends, but especially family. As hard as it was at times, I could never bring myself to leave because I was too comfortable to move and because I believed the Lord still wanted me here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For personal reasons, my week in Vancouver was very hard, a situation multiplied by the international factor prohibiting any phone calls to my family. I did a lot of thinking that week about packing up and moving on, even though I knew in my heart that I wouldn’t unless God clearly showed me I was to leave. Then unexpectedly on that Monday morning, God showed me the next step in His will.  And the event that I always viewed as a terrible thing made me smile because I knew my God cared for me and was making it easy for me to follow Him into the next adventure. It’s a funny thing about God, he likes to do things “backwards” but perfectly: first = last, humble = exalted, poor = rich, downsized = excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I finished up my work with the company and “put my affairs in order.” Then I flew out east for an absolute humdinger of a whirlwind tour with my family for Thanksgiving. Saying it was a great time would be an understatement. I am now back in Payson for a last few days packing up my few things in preparation to move home. My sister Sarah is flying out here tomorrow morning and we’ll be driving my Grandma Car back home. That should be a lot of fun. The church youth group is having a “We’re Mad at You for Leaving” party Wednesday night. Of all the things I’ll miss here in Arizona, by far the biggest will be the wonderful church family I have had the privilege of worshiping with this last year and some months. Ponderosa Baptist is a church where the majority of the people are doing ministry with the church is some way: it is a church that blows the 80-20 rule out of the water. It’s a beautiful thing to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now some people may think that this excursion to Payson has been a dead end that wasted many valuable months. In fact I am surprised that I don’t feel a little like that, but I find that I cannot be regretful in light of the many important things I’ve learned here. This post is already too long to list them all, and I’m sure I would forget some. I’m not sure if Payson, as a geographical location was so important, but the isolation from family and former friends, the unique mix of coworkers and new friends, and the special opportunities and challenges combined to make this “Payson Experience” a significant and necessary step in my personal growth. And let’s face it: Payson is a pretty nice place to live with one of the best climates I’ve ever experienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I move ahead. I must confess I really don’t know what I’ll be doing next, other than spending a nice December with my family. January is an open slate and rather than worry about it, I’ll trust God that He will fill in the details in His way in His time. He’s done it before and He can do it again. Frankly, I’m pretty excited to see what God does! This is my Thanksgiving, and God is the hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 37:3-7a</title>
      <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/thursday-august-2-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/thursday-august-2-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once again I find myself reading Psalm 37.
&amp;ldquo;Trust in the LORD, and do good; so shalt thou dwell in the land, and verily thou shalt be fed. Delight thyself also in the LORD; and He shall give thee the desires of thine heart. Commit thy way unto the LORD; trust also in him; and He shall bring it to pass. And He shall bring forth thy righteousness as the light, and thy judgment as the noonday. Rest in the LORD, and wait patiently for Him.&amp;ldquo;  ~ Psalm 37:3-7a
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday July 24, 2007</title>
      <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/tuesday-july-24-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/tuesday-july-24-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I get really mad today. Which is surprising since I&amp;rsquo;m a really easy going person and not much shakes me in that way. I can&amp;rsquo;t remember being mad for months, and then I&amp;rsquo;m fuming. It was kind of scary: I was seconds away from saying some imprudent things. As 1 Corinthians 10:12 says, &amp;ldquo;Wherefore let him that thinketh he standeth take heed lest he fall.&amp;rdquo; Fortunately I took heed and called my Mom where she was able to get my mind back on good things (Philippians 4:8).
It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that 1 Corinthians 10:12 is proceeded by some verses on the Israelites in the desert in verses 1-11. &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; brethren, I would not that ye should be ignorant, how that all our fathers were under the cloud, and all passed through the sea; and were all baptized unto Moses in the cloud and in the sea; and did eat the same spiritual meat; and did drink the same spiritual drink: for the drank of that spiritual Rock that followed them: and that Rock was Christ. But with many of them God was not pleased: for they were overthrown in the wilderness. &amp;hellip; Neither be ye idolaters &amp;hellip; commit fornication &amp;hellip; tempt Christ &amp;hellip; murmur &amp;hellip; as some of them &amp;hellip; and were destroyed of the destroyer. Now these things happened unto them for ensamples: and they are written for our admonition, upon whom the ends of the world are come.&amp;rdquo; Then finally, &amp;ldquo;Wherefore let him that thinketh he standeth take heed lest he fall.&amp;rdquo;
And it&amp;rsquo;s so easy to get caught up in Christless actions and attitudes. Take heed. I got a big warning today. Thank God for Mom!
Ryan
By the way, my xanga is now 2¹° days old.
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

