<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>On-A-Personal-Note on Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/on-a-personal-note/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday August 16, 2007</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/thursday-august-16-2007</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/thursday-august-16-2007</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And so I pose the question.
What&amp;rsquo;s your favorite: red or triangles?
I&amp;rsquo;m teaching the youth Sunday school on (you guessed it) Sunday. I&amp;rsquo;m teaching on the great American founder whose numerous influences spread to medicine (primarily), education, prison reform, Sunday schools, Bible societies, women&amp;rsquo;s education, and abolition of slavery. Yes: Dr. Benjamin Rush. He said, &amp;ldquo;I am neither an Aristocrat nor a Democrat. I am a Christ-ocrat.&amp;rdquo; It should be fun.
So Byron (my house-mate) is proposing to Christy (his girlfriend) this weekend. I guess we&amp;rsquo;ll see how this goes. (Actually, I think it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much a given that she&amp;rsquo;ll say yes.)
On a personal note: triangles.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday July 7, 2007</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/saturday-july-7-2007</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/saturday-july-7-2007</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel excited because of my wound. But I&amp;rsquo;m not especially excited. Whenever I get really excited in an anticipatory way my lower gums get tingly and numb. And this sore on the inside of my lower lip is making my gums tingly and numb. So I keep wondering why I feel so vaguely excited&amp;hellip;
I went to the coffeeshop and read for a while. &amp;lsquo;Twas a good time: I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been in a while. And there was a guy trying to sing old-timey country, so that makes the experience even more colorful.
On a personal note, &amp;ldquo;The Lord of the Shoehorn&amp;rdquo; sounds like a good title.
&amp;ldquo;Enveloped in smoke and the burning of flames,
And the tumult of voices without any names,
Sitting high on a throne of white, porcelain mold
Reins the Lord of the Shoehorn, by whom men are soled.
And the traveler&amp;rsquo;s feet have been fated to stay
Weakly barefoot and feeble &amp;lsquo;til booted away.&amp;rdquo;
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday June 7, 2007</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/thursday-june-7-2007</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/thursday-june-7-2007</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And so I started my second year as a contributing member of society (yikes, that sounded Marxist). The second year started much more buoyantly than year one ended. Good news.
On a personal note: what if you woke up one morning and found that you had actually dropped off the face of the planet. For real.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>