<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wedding on Ryan Clarke</title>
    <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/tags/wedding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wedding on Ryan Clarke</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2017 Ryan Clarke</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//www.ryanclarke.net/tags/wedding/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday November 21, 2007</title>
      <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/wednesday-november-21-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/wednesday-november-21-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The wedding was amazing. I have spent the last few days at home and now we&amp;rsquo;re all headed up to North Carolina for Thanksgiving. Here&amp;rsquo;s wishing you all a happy Thanksgiving and a grateful heart.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday November 14, 2007</title>
      <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/wednesday-november-14-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/wednesday-november-14-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m headed east! I&amp;rsquo;m spending a day at Verity before heading down to my good friend Bryce&amp;rsquo;s wedding where I&amp;rsquo;ll be the best man. Then I spend the whole following week and Thanksgiving with my family. This is going to be fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monday August 13, 2007</title>
      <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/monday-august-13-2007-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/monday-august-13-2007-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The wedding was great. In fact, the entire weekend was a blast. I&amp;rsquo;ll post more later.
Ryan
P.S. This post was mostly for Mom&amp;rsquo;s benefit so she can know that I got home safely.
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monday August 13, 2007</title>
      <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/monday-august-13-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/monday-august-13-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The wedding was very lovely, although not in the usual sense. It was clean. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t all the crazy fluff and froo-froo that normally accompanies weddings. Just 15 hymns, 2 sermons, and some heartfelt vows. Then we went to the reception. The grove (which I mentioned before) we all decked out with glowing orbs hanging from the trees and tiki lanterns around the pond and reflecting off the water. Beneath were table and chairs for eating the delicious treats they had laid out. Heather was there, and so I show you the only picture I had taken during the entire party. Amy, Josh, me, and Heather.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://photo.xanga.com/classicalRyan/d9378141588072/photo.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://xd9.xanga.com/378d9b2b75d30141588072/b104456194.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Strickler Wedding&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Also, Luke Johnson was there but I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a picture. And so we eventually saw the new couple off for their adventure in Boston. And we returned to the house to throw the leftover candies in the air and try to catch them in our mouths. I cannot hold a candle to the Strickler family in that skill area.
On Sunday morning we went to church. The worship service style was very old fashioned as was the music also. It was really neat to get to participate. The have an extensive sharing and testimonial time during the first hours of the service and I exercised great self-control and did not stand up and blab. Then they asked if any visitors would like to share, so I acquiesced. I read Ephesians 4:3-6. Afterwards during the succulent potluck many folks thanked me for sharing. I guess giving testimonials is highly regarded and encouraged, so they were very happy that a guest joined in. I was just moved to partake of the rich spiritual unity among such different traditional customs. They had a lot of dessert.
Flying out I sat next to an Israeli guy who makes processors for Nikon cameras. He&amp;rsquo;s doing four months of job training her in Phoenix. He was reading a Russian book (that, interestingly, had a Japanese guy on the front).
In Phoenix I was able to get right into my car, which was a great relief, because going out there I had left my keys in the ignition. But I had the shuttle bus guy drive me back to the lot and the car was unlocked and I got my keys and all. So I had no trouble coming home. What a dumb stunt that was though.
The Strickler family is one of the most hospitable families I&amp;rsquo;ve ever met. The entire trip was a blast. I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I went and it was good to see Josh get all happily married off.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday August 11, 2007</title>
      <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/saturday-august-11-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/saturday-august-11-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s a little slower around here now. Everyone of importance is out taking pictures. Or rather, having pictures of themselves taken.
I am thoroughly enjoying having a blast here. I&amp;rsquo;m staying with the Stricklers and it is definitely the place to be. The whole family is fun and energetic. Yesterday and this morning we spent a lot of time getting the Strickler&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;backyard&amp;rdquo; ready for the reception. It&amp;rsquo;s in the &amp;lsquo;grove&amp;rsquo; next to the pond. I put grove within marks because it&amp;rsquo;s unlike a normal grove. Their grandfather loved trees so he planted over 300 different types of trees around the farm (some of which has since been sold off to make a highway). The grove has about 30 huge trees of several varieties including a redwood and the back side of the pond has about 40 more types. The evergreen windbreak in front of the house is equally varied. It&amp;rsquo;s actually a really neat look. So the reception is ready. Also, Josh and I got his new radio wired into his car. So it looks like everything is in order for the wedding this evening at the church and then the reception afterward.
I wish more of you Verity friends of Josh could have come, you&amp;rsquo;d be having a blast too.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday August 9, 2007</title>
      <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/thursday-august-9-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/thursday-august-9-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have this one day of work and then I leave for Harrisburg, PA. I&amp;rsquo;m flying through the night out to Josh Strickler&amp;rsquo;s wedding. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty excited about the whole trip. I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll pack tonight after work.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

