<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Christmas on Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/tags/christmas/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
    <copyright>© Ryan Clarke, 2014</copyright>
    <updated>Mon, 24 Dec 2007 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Tis What Season...?</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/tis-what-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/tis-what-season/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By the way, what season is it anyway? I was at Best Buy last night and I walked over to the table where they were selling the holiday gift cards. I say &amp;ldquo;holiday&amp;rdquo; with purpose. I&amp;rsquo;m not using it as a contraction of holy and day used for Christian celebrations, I&amp;rsquo;m using it as an all-purpose, non-religious term for the 25th of December, or more, Thanksgiving through New Year&amp;rsquo;s Day. (When was the last time you wished someone a happy holiday for July 4th? What about the Late Spring Holiday Season of Mother&amp;rsquo;s Day, Memorial Day, Father&amp;rsquo;s Day and Flag day?) So I&amp;rsquo;m standing at the gift card table and there are four different styles to suit everyone: Happy Kwanzaa, Happy Hanukkah, Love and Holiday (with a bride and a groom on it) and Giving Season with a gift. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t a &amp;ldquo;Christmas&amp;rdquo;, a manger, or a angel to be seen. Not even a serene looking female angel with long flaxen hair and a trumpet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I&amp;rsquo;m saying is that Christmas was a very big thing: God became man. It deserves a big celebration, and now it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even get a mention from corporate people who &amp;lsquo;know.&amp;rsquo; Sometimes it feels like they have taken the Christ out of Christmas and now they are destroying the last remnant of the X in Xmas. But I can still worship the newborn Christ, and that&amp;rsquo;s what I plan to do, whether it&amp;rsquo;s officially endorsed by Best Buy or not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>