<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/tags/church/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
    <copyright>© 2015 Ryan Clarke</copyright>
    <updated>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday October 7, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/sunday-october-7-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/sunday-october-7-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My second weekend filling in for Pastor Allen with the youth is over. I have really enjoyed the opportunity to share more powerfully with the kids, but it&amp;rsquo;s tiring. God really blessed me and helped me. Last night at youth group I taught about anger and the good and bad kinds and how to correctly deal with it. This morning in Sunday School I taught the final lesson in a series called Totally Consumed about being an authentic worshiper. It was the lesson on revival and how revivals start with prayer and repentance in the lives of believers. &amp;ldquo;Revival starts with me.&amp;rdquo; Only as we show the world what a true believer looks like can they be attracted by our ambassadorship to Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another week of work comes ahead and then the youth trip to Magic Mountain to ride some roller coasters and listen to some good Christian youth speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday September 29, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/saturday-september-29-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/saturday-september-29-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We made enough money at the church yard sale to send all the youth students on the retreat to California! It was quite a success, but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty tired now. Okay, very tired. Filling in for Pastor Allen is not an easy job. And tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m teaching Sunday School for him too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also tomorrow I plan to swing by the 37th Annual Old-Time Fiddlers Contest. How could I miss something like that? It&amp;rsquo;s a busy weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monday September 17, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/monday-september-17-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/monday-september-17-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw Herbie again and I still haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to take a picture. Yeah, he lives in my town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I played a little paintball today and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to report that my gun, with it&amp;rsquo;s new low-pressure mod (that I finally completed), performed admirably and I&amp;rsquo;m quite happy with the improvement. Not that you care, but you might be interested to know that I shot about 5 balls into the trunk of my car by mistake. Fortunately I hit some other paintball stuff in there so my fine gray carpet (I guess that what you call it) is not a mysteriously tie-dyed design like I had feared. &amp;ldquo;Fear&amp;rdquo; is probably a harsher term than necessary for my peculiar emotion: &amp;ldquo;surprised &amp;lsquo;huh&amp;rsquo;-ness&amp;rdquo; would be a more exact term. I&amp;rsquo;m just glad it didn&amp;rsquo;t happen to Herbie. Needless to say, since I was the winner of that little duel it had to carry me home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the final test for my evangelism training class. It was a very long handwritten test. By the end of it I was so cramped that my handwriting was changing styles faster than women&amp;rsquo;s clothing. It didn&amp;rsquo;t help that I keenly felt the pressure of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll wake up tomorrow and my cold will be gone. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t that be exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday September 2, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/sunday-september-2-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/sunday-september-2-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spoke at men&amp;rsquo;s breakfast at church this morning. It went really well.
Tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m heading out with some guys deep into the mountains for an overnight camping trip. We&amp;rsquo;ll be back later on Monday.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday August 26, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/sunday-august-26-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/sunday-august-26-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The choir men sang the special during church today. It was a killer-hard 3-part men&amp;rsquo;s piece. But after several weeks of practice we pretty much had it nailed and it came off well. We got tons of compliments and I even got 3 about my voice in particular. What can I say: I sing loud. So maybe my voice is improving into a viable, public-use instrument of praise.
We played paintball this afternoon. It&amp;rsquo;s always a blast. We played 4 games with 4 on 4 teams. Out of the 18 total eliminations made by both teams today, I shot 9 of them. I must have been on a roll. And I&amp;rsquo;m tired from running up and down the sides of the dirt gullys.
By the way, my listening on Wednesday night worked. The guy managed to talk himself into doing the right thing. He knew the truth and he was having trouble seeing it because of a few bad days: and I listen to him talk himself into the right. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how that works.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday August 16, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/thursday-august-16-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/thursday-august-16-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And so I pose the question.
What&amp;rsquo;s your favorite: red or triangles?
I&amp;rsquo;m teaching the youth Sunday school on (you guessed it) Sunday. I&amp;rsquo;m teaching on the great American founder whose numerous influences spread to medicine (primarily), education, prison reform, Sunday schools, Bible societies, women&amp;rsquo;s education, and abolition of slavery. Yes: Dr. Benjamin Rush. He said, &amp;ldquo;I am neither an Aristocrat nor a Democrat. I am a Christ-ocrat.&amp;rdquo; It should be fun.
So Byron (my house-mate) is proposing to Christy (his girlfriend) this weekend. I guess we&amp;rsquo;ll see how this goes. (Actually, I think it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much a given that she&amp;rsquo;ll say yes.)
On a personal note: triangles.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday July 14, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/saturday-july-14-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/saturday-july-14-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To do:
Sat. 8-Noon: fund raiser car wash with the church youth.
Sat. 5-Midnight: trip to Chandler to hear an Answers in Genesis speaker
Sun. 7:30-11:30am: Church
Sun. 6-7pm: Evangelism Explosion training
Mon. 7am: Fly to Vancouver, BC to work 15+ hour days
Just when things were beginning to calm down, they are as crazy as ever again. Wait, they were beginning to calm down? Since when? At least I&amp;rsquo;m doing what I enjoy.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 40:9-10</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/psalm-40-9-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/psalm-40-9-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have proclaimed glad tidings of righteousness in the great congregation; Behold, I will not restrain my lips, O Lord, Thou knowest. I have not hidden Thy righteousness within my heart; I have spoken of Thy faithfulness and Thy salvation; I have not concealed Thy lovingkindness and Thy truth from the great congregation.&amp;rdquo;
     ~ Psalm 40:9-10
Most scholars agree (okay, I only checked with Spurgeon&amp;rsquo;s Treasury of Psalms) that this passage, and much of the entire Psalm, is written about Christ and His unwavering proclamation of the Kingdom of God&amp;rsquo;s imminence during His years of ministry. When I read this passage this morning my first thought was on the evangelism training I&amp;rsquo;m going through with my church. When I insert my self in there, and switch all &amp;ldquo;the great congregations&amp;rdquo; out for the &amp;ldquo;the world&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;lost and helpless people.&amp;rdquo;
May I be worthy of the task.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday June 2, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/saturday-june-2-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/saturday-june-2-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight at youth we played capture the flag.
With squirt guns.
With food coloring.
It was a blast. (Haha, get it?)
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday June 1, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/friday-june-1-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/friday-june-1-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night after work I went over to my coworker Joseph&amp;rsquo;s house and we ate pizza and watched Robots. Laughed our heads off. &amp;ldquo;Good luck with your dastardly plans.&amp;rdquo;
I also got a tax document in the mail saying I miscalculated my AZ tax return. They owe me \$203 dollars more than I thought. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how in the world I got that wrong. At least I was off in the right direction. Thank you, God, for the unexpected little boost! Because&amp;hellip;
Today the rent is due. Again. With all the regularity of those dashed lines on the road. And Cheese-its, which are always gone the day after you open the box.
On a slightly different note. It&amp;rsquo;s always fun it introduce myself to someone while I&amp;rsquo;m wearing my work uniform that has a name patch. &amp;ldquo;Hello, my name is&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; well, yesterday&amp;hellip; just a second&amp;hellip; *checks name patch*&amp;hellip; Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Ryan.&amp;rdquo;
I joined the choir. And everyone is still coming to church.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

