<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Windows on Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/tags/windows/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
    <copyright>© Ryan Clarke, 2014</copyright>
    <updated>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 09:00:00 EDT</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Pinned Site Live Tile easily and without pain</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/creating-a-pinned-site-live-tile-easily-and-without-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 09:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/creating-a-pinned-site-live-tile-easily-and-without-pain/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The list of things a developer must add to their website is constantly growing. I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about the big things; I&amp;rsquo;m talking about the little stuff that would be stupid to leave out. For instance, favicons were introduced by Internet Explorer 5 in 1999 (they made it into the HTML 4.01 recommendation later that year). Your site would function just as well without a favicon but you would be crazy not to have one. It&amp;rsquo;s basically a requirement. The same thing goes for the description meta tag and apple-touch-icon, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now there&amp;rsquo;s another one: Pinned Site Live Tiles as implemented by IE11 in Windows 8.1 and Windows Phone 8.1. Pinned SLTs (which I call &amp;ldquo;slivets&amp;rdquo;) allows a website to have a series of beautiful images for the different sizes of Windows tiles and even allows the display of website information using some lovely built-in tile templates using a simple xml schema.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a little more involved than, say, a favicon but it&amp;rsquo;s really not hard. Especially for the value you get. Microsoft has a lot of documentation to make this easy. What can be hard is finding the right page since it&amp;rsquo;s not all in one place. Here are some links to help you avoid wasted time and pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Quick start&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.buildmypinnedsite.com&#34; title=&#34;http://www.buildmypinnedsite.com&#34;&gt;buildmypinnedsite.com&lt;/a&gt;- This is the very first place you should go if you want slivets. This easy wizard will get you up and running in no time. You will probably want to replace the images with something more professional and customize the urls to match your site, but it quickly gives you something that&amp;rsquo;s working and gives you a good place from which to start customizing. It&amp;rsquo;s basically the File &amp;gt; New of slivets. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/MakeAWindows81PinnedLiveTileForYOURWebsiteInMinutes.aspx&#34; title=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/MakeAWindows81PinnedLiveTileForYOURWebsiteInMinutes.aspx&#34;&gt;Make a Windows 8.1 Pinned Live Tile for YOUR website in minutes&lt;/a&gt; - I&amp;rsquo;m not going to give a complete how-to because Scott Hanselman already has and his is better than mine would be. He walks you through the wizard site above and explains what it all means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Designing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ie/dn455115%28v=vs.85%29.aspx&#34; title=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ie/dn455115%28v=vs.85%29.aspx&#34;&gt;Create live tiles for your websites in IE11&lt;/a&gt; - This is the jumping off place to explore the Microsoft help for slivets. Start here with questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ie/hh772707%28v=vs.85%29.aspx&#34; title=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ie/hh772707%28v=vs.85%29.aspx&#34;&gt;Pinned Sites&lt;/a&gt; - This the jumping off place to explore the Microsoft API documentation for pinned sites including schemas for the browser config, for html meta tags, and the complete list of properties, methods and events used by the browser. This is really helpful for pulling off some cool and crazy website-to-slivet interactions with the variety of available javascript hooks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ie/hh761491.aspx&#34; title=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ie/hh761491.aspx&#34;&gt;The tile template catalog (Windows Runtime apps)&lt;/a&gt; - You&amp;rsquo;ll want to pick your tiles to fit the data you are displaying. This is the comprehensive list of all possible tiles with example xml and result photo to get you started. You should find several you like. Of course, you can make the tile look like whatever you want by simply picking the single photo template and generating the custom-formatted image yourself. But that would take more server infrastructure on your end and would risk making your tiles clash with the aesthetic of the OS. Still, the option is there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Debugging&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ie/dn439794%28v=vs.85%29.aspx&#34; title=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ie/dn439794%28v=vs.85%29.aspx&#34;&gt;Build a live tile&lt;/a&gt; - This starts out as Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s how-to guide but important part is at the very bottom under &amp;ldquo;Testing and finding problems with live tiles.&amp;rdquo; Slivets are designed to light up with whatever pieces are present and if they aren&amp;rsquo;t there, fallback to normal behavior. This is really nice for end-users, but it can make development difficult because when something doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, IE is quite taciturn about reasons. The tips at this link are simple but indispensable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telerik.com/fiddler&#34; title=&#34;http://www.telerik.com/fiddler&#34;&gt;Fiddler&lt;/a&gt; - While we are on the topic of debugging, you pretty much have to have Fiddler to monitor the network traffic. This will tell you if the endpoints you defined are even being hit. I wasted a couple hours trying to solve a seemingly impossible problem with my slivets, but after I used Fiddler I solved the problem in minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need any more help feel free to contact me. Of course, if you&amp;rsquo;d like to talk to someone who actually knows something, I&amp;rsquo;ve found Microsoft Program Managers &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MattHidinger&#34; title=&#34;Twitter @MattHidinger&#34;&gt;MattHidinger&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jacobrossi&#34; title=&#34;Twitter @jacobrossi&#34;&gt;Jacob Rossi&lt;/a&gt; to be quick, friendly and very helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinned Site Live Tiles belong on all sites</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/pinned-site-live-tiles-belong-on-all-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 08:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/pinned-site-live-tiles-belong-on-all-sites/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Imagine if you could take your existing website and turn it into an app with minimal effort. Of course, that&amp;rsquo;s impossible. But you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; get 75%* of the way there with an awesome new Internet Explorer feature I recently implemented on one of SEP&amp;rsquo;s sites called Pinned Site Live Tiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;What are Pinned Site Live Tiles?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure you are familiar with live tiles. They first came with the launch of Windows Phone and now are a defining feature of Windows 8+ as well. Live tiles allow apps that have been pinned to the user&amp;rsquo;s start screen to update their tile with dynamically generated and presumably relevant information. Pinned SLTs (which I will now call slivets) bring that feature to Windows 8.1&amp;rsquo;s IE11 when you pin a web link to the start screen. They basically transform a simple bookmark with a blurry favicon into something almost indistinguishable from a real app. Scott Hanselman wrote an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/MakeAWindows81PinnedLiveTileForYOURWebsiteInMinutes.aspx&#34; title=&#34;Make a Windows 8.1 Pinned Live Tile for YOUR website in minutes&#34;&gt;easy how-to guide&lt;/a&gt; on his blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But things just got better. Nestled deep within &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/matthidinger&#34; title=&#34;Twitter @MattHidinger&#34;&gt;Matt Hidinger&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s interesting &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/Build/2014/2-523&#34; title=&#34;MSDN Channel9&#34;&gt;Live Tiles Enhancements&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; talk from Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s BUILD conference was a cool little revelation: slivets work on Windows Phone 8.1 as well as Windows 8.1. So now they work on all of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s desktop, tablet, and phone platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;A Disclaimer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;rsquo;s worth mentioning that slivets only work when IE11 is the default browser. But that limitation doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter since it won&amp;rsquo;t affect your target audience. Anyone interested in apps, namely users of Windows tablets and Windows Phones, are almost certain to have IE as their default browser. And frankly, many desktop users never change their default browser away from IE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;The Case for Pinned Site Live Tiles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slivets work for almost the entire the app-inclined Windows user base and for all of Windows Phone users. This is a large market, and although currently perched at third place in worldwide market share, it is an underserved market too. Some may scoff at the size of this user base in comparison with Android and iOS. But anyone with a great website who wants apps is likely already going the Android/iOS route since they give the most bang for the many bucks it takes to build an app. That leaves just the Windows platforms in need of apps, and slivets fills those exact markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can enable one of the signature Windows platforms&amp;rsquo; features just by adding a couple meta tags to your header and a few xml files. Who cares about bang vs. buck when the price is nearly free. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s so easy that even if you don&amp;rsquo;t have iOS/Android apps you should still enable slivets, the same way you would be silly not to include an apple-touch-icon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From now on, I plan to add slivets to all the websites I build unless it&amp;rsquo;s unnecessary or technically impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adding slivets to your site is not difficult, but there are some tricky situations that can waste your time if you don&amp;rsquo;t know where to look for answers. I&amp;rsquo;ve included some more technical information and helpful tips in my companion article, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanclarke.net/post/creating-a-pinned-site-live-tile-easily-and-without-pain/&#34; title=&#34;How to create a Pinned Site Live Tile without pain&#34;&gt;How to create a Pinned Site Live Tile without pain&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Disclaimer: invented number.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>