<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/tags/music/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
    <copyright>© 2015 Ryan Clarke</copyright>
    <updated>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday September 29, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/saturday-september-29-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/saturday-september-29-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We made enough money at the church yard sale to send all the youth students on the retreat to California! It was quite a success, but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty tired now. Okay, very tired. Filling in for Pastor Allen is not an easy job. And tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m teaching Sunday School for him too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also tomorrow I plan to swing by the 37th Annual Old-Time Fiddlers Contest. How could I miss something like that? It&amp;rsquo;s a busy weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday June 1, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/friday-june-1-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/friday-june-1-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night after work I went over to my coworker Joseph&amp;rsquo;s house and we ate pizza and watched Robots. Laughed our heads off. &amp;ldquo;Good luck with your dastardly plans.&amp;rdquo;
I also got a tax document in the mail saying I miscalculated my AZ tax return. They owe me \$203 dollars more than I thought. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how in the world I got that wrong. At least I was off in the right direction. Thank you, God, for the unexpected little boost! Because&amp;hellip;
Today the rent is due. Again. With all the regularity of those dashed lines on the road. And Cheese-its, which are always gone the day after you open the box.
On a slightly different note. It&amp;rsquo;s always fun it introduce myself to someone while I&amp;rsquo;m wearing my work uniform that has a name patch. &amp;ldquo;Hello, my name is&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; well, yesterday&amp;hellip; just a second&amp;hellip; *checks name patch*&amp;hellip; Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Ryan.&amp;rdquo;
I joined the choir. And everyone is still coming to church.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

