<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/project/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
    <copyright>© 2015 Ryan Clarke</copyright>
    <updated>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 01:22:35 EDT</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>TalkTimer</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/project/talktimer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 01:22:35 EDT</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/project/talktimer/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;How often have you needed a simple timer app that counts down the minutes and seconds to zero? If you said even once, then you might benefit from this app. Ninety-eight and three quarters percent guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app will start counting at whatever minute you specify. But not just the numbers change. The app turns bold new colors at the two and one minute milestones. &amp;ldquo;Warning, you are almost done!&amp;rdquo; When the time finally expires, the app hits a mellifluous gong. Of course, the gong can be turned off if you are using the app covertly and silence is a must. Your choice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s more: &amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo; is not the last number that the app displays! Using the power of negative integers, this app can show you how many minutes have elapsed since the gong/silence. Killer feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use this app to time the lightning talks I host at my company (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sep.com&#34;&gt;SEP&lt;/a&gt;). Over the course of an hour, four speakers have 10 minutes each to share something interesting (or else!). As soon as the gong reverberates they are required by extreme social pressure to quit presenting. They then have a few minutes to endure an audience cross-examination while the next presenter makes sacrifices to the projector in hopes that it will deem his slidedeck worthy of display. If this app seems tailor made to fit this scenario, it is simply because I tailor made it (artisanally) to fit this scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Available now on all your devices! &lt;em&gt;as long as they run Windows 8.1+ or Windows Phone 8.1+.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://apps.microsoft.com/windows/app/talktimer/ea2e3a6d-8931-4e63-8cee-4872f519b677&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ryanclarke.net/images/project/WindowsStore_badge_en_English_Green_med_258x67.png&#34; alt=&#34;Windows Store link&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.windowsphone.com/en-us/store/app/talktimer/c1dcaefe-298d-42ce-858a-847d7fc7d6a9&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ryanclarke.net/images/project/258x67_WPS_Download_cyan.png&#34; alt=&#34;Windows Phone Store link&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app knows nothing about anything. Privacy policy unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crosswind</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/project/crosswind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/project/crosswind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While on vacation with my parents earlier this year, my father, the airline pilot, asked me to make him an app. Often when he’s coming in for a landing he wants to know the crosswind on the runway. He knows the runway heading, he knows the wind heading and speed, he knows he has robust tools in his fight kit to do the calculations. But all he really wants to know is if the crosswind is close enough to the plane’s crosswind rating to worry about it. He wants an estimate, he wants it quick, and he wants to get on with the landing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I built Crosswind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crosswind is a single-purpose Windows Phone app that can take three inputs, do a sine for the result, and get out of the way. It was designed to be simple, beautiful, and (most of all) fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ryanclarke.net/images/project/crosswind/CrosswindMainPage.png&#34; alt=&#34;Crosswind Main Page&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I receive my commission at the end of May, I didn’t start work on Crosswind until the beginning of August during the Summer 2014 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sep.com/labs/startupweekend/&#34;&gt;SEP Startup Weekend&lt;/a&gt;. It wasn’t until this last week that I had an opportunity to finish it up and publish it. I have probably put 40 hours into it so far and though there are still several changes I’d like to make to the code, it is published and live on the Windows Phone app store. It is my first mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While working on the app I found a couple of very awesome sites. &lt;a href=&#34;http://rgb.to&#34;&gt;RGB.to&lt;/a&gt; is a great resource for converting colors between different formats. e.g. hex to HSL. It even supports HTML color names (which Windows Phone also uses). The other is &lt;a href=&#34;http://modernuiicons.com&#34;&gt;ModernUIIcons.com&lt;/a&gt;, an large, high-quality, free icon pack that really embraces the Windows Phone aesthetic. I will certainly be using more of those icons in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, the link you’ve all been waiting for: check out “Crosswind” in the Windows Phone Store! &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.windowsphone.com/en-us/store/app/crosswind/285e269d-0574-46ac-97e7-7f5386d154b2&#34;&gt;http://www.windowsphone.com/en-us/store/app/crosswind/285e269d-0574-46ac-97e7-7f5386d154b2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.windowsphone.com/en-us/store/app/crosswind/285e269d-0574-46ac-97e7-7f5386d154b2&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ryanclarke.net/images/project/258x67_WPS_Download_cyan.png&#34; alt=&#34;Windows Phone Store link&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one’s for you, Dad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

