<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Xanga on Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/categories/xanga/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>True Adventure</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/true-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/true-adventure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“True adventurers have never been plentiful. They who are set down in print as such have been mostly business men with newly invented methods. They have been out after the things they wanted—golden fleeces, holy grails, lady loves, treasure, crowns and fame. The true adventurer goes forth aimless and uncalculating to meet and greet unknown fate. A fine example was the Prodigal Son&amp;ndash;when he started back home.” ~O. Henry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That paragraph from &lt;em&gt;The Green Door&lt;/em&gt; captures the essence of the Christian Adventure. Life is designed to require faith and the life of faith is an Adventure. For some years now I have felt called by God to go to China and learn the Chinese language and I think, “Won’t living in China be an adventure!” However, China is not the Christian Adventure. The Adventure is feeling and following the call of God when it looks impossible. It is desperately caring about the success of a situation when it is shadowed by certain failure in human terms. It is diving whole-heartedly into vague visions of the future when there is no earthly way that it will all work out. It is stepping into the Jordan River in hopes that God will dry it out. The Christian Adventure cannot be separated from prayer: kneeling in the darkness night after night and begging God for direction, begging Him for faith, begging for peace and confidence and contentment and joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Christian Adventure is being willing to calmly follow God into crushing trials because He has promised to never leave me and to work everything together for my good. It is passionately living under the will of Divine Benevolence. Do I have to go to China for adventure? No, I am living the Adventure now. And it just might be that the Adventure will lead me to China. God knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rest my unknown future on Christ who died for me. That is True Adventure and I am a True Adventurer!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 Year in Review</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/2008-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/2008-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Reflections upon a memory fail as a strict measure of the past. Some memories tend to dim while others are being distorted through age and perception. Many memories simply slip into forgotten corners whence they are sometimes revived through odd happenstances. What follows is a summary of my own incomplete but genuine recollections upon my journey through 2008.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began the year as cheerfully as I ended 2007. One started as the other stopped in as smooth a transition as is normally expected between the two.  I remember my first thoughts of 2008 revolved around bed and sleep. This year began like most others at the unearthly hour of midnight.  Of course, I stay up until 12am and later on a regular basis throughout the year, but very few such nightly vigils are preceded by such enthusiastic revelry. I began the year happy, tired, and free. I also had several large issues weighing much lighter on my mind than a nervous person would ever allow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, my future: the entire, unfathomable mass of it lay in stretched before me like an invisible question mark. I was recently self-unemployed since my company had some financial troubles and released one-ninth of the entire workforce. I was the lucky one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in Arizona I prayed about an opportunity at romance. It really was a good opportunity, it just lacked the romance. They say that a successful courtship is one in which God’s will is successful. You would have trouble calling that a courtship, but I rest happily with the result knowing that God’s leading was honored. As I understand, the young lady is doing well and living strong for the Lord. I will say no more on this subject since it would be in poor taste. Since it happened that this all turned out about the time of my self-unemployment, I felt Arizona held much less charm for me. I gathered the few valuable possessions that were small enough to fit in the car and left Arizona for my hometown in Georgia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus financially and emotionally free, I looked out upon 2008 with a bright eye which saw no clues as to my future direction. God did not leave me like this long. Two wonderful employment opportunities hit at about the same time. I was working a trial week with a local environmental engineer and we both liked the arrangement and I enjoyed the hefty pay when I received a summons to mold young minds. When the call is given; when the call is received; and most importantly, when the call is intensely desired; I respond.  Verity Institute, my beloved alma mater, requested my services as a guest instructor. How it all came to be was quite interesting, but it makes a poor story so I will skip it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This explains why I started reading massive books on Financial Accounting with such zeal. I hold that there is no better person to teach people about money than one who has very little of it. That statement is of questionable accuracy but it is precisely the situation I found before me. The class was, in all honesty, a bit rough, but the students fared alright in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winters in the Midwest are a little more dramatic than the ones in Georgia. Having spent the last few winters in Michigan and Arizona, I like a good layer of snow. It was perfect for snowball fights and sledding and the ski trip to Michigan. Even the thaw time provided good fun with some 6am boating in Taylor’s Pond in unsafe temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring brought with it a lovely rest over Holy week. Cameron Houser visited with me and my family in Georgia for the break. The highlight of the trip was definitely hiking up Stone Mountain, first with the Verity ’07 class reunion-goers and then the next day with the Verity ’08 and ’09 folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the spring at Verity I spent almost all my time teaching the Harmony classes to the Verity music students.  I would teach from a chair all day and then go down to the student lounge where I could tutor from a couch. It was a long, tiring, and perfectly delightful time. I thoroughly enjoy teaching music theory. All the students passed the final exam with good scores. Praise God!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summer break happened fast. I spent a lot of time playing soccer out front with Andrew and Ben. I also did a lot of studying. That is one of those things about people who like to learn, any weather is good for studying. Rainy, foggy, sweltering, windy, freezing, humid, you name it, they say, “This is a perfect day to just curl up with a good book and go to sleep!” I somewhat agree, but it is also a good day to play soccer, so people just have to learn how to split up their time. I look at myself when I say this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished up the summer with a nice vacation to Mexico where I had some fun with my good amigo Josh Rodriguez. We built him a powerful Windows machine so he could do high-quality recording and composing on it. It is a nice computer. We went to the Museum of Mexican History and some grottos found by a monk and got pulled over by a cop for driving in the middle lane of a highway that had no lanes. That lecture cost us about \$12 US so I plan to remember it, but we did learn a really neat shortcut from him, one with no cops on it, so it turned out to be a fair trade. Of course, I got the entire thing second hand from JRod since foreign countries still have a tendency to speak foreign languages, especially during official government business proceedings along the turnpike. The Rodriguez family is about the most friendly, fun, and hospitable group of people you could hope to visit. Also, they have a delicious taquito place just around the corner from their house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In mid-July I returned to Verity as an official staffer with all the privileges responsibilities thereof: one of those being the privilege of working for Dr. McCray. I will say this, that the Verity work environment is almost unimaginable in its pleasantness. Doing something I really enjoy with people I enjoy doing it with is a grand situation. I am the reigning and undisputed Vice President of Intelligence, although my official title is Curriculum Development Assistant. I work for the Curriculum Development Coordinator, Charity Larson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We in Curriculum Development are the heart of Verity. Not only do we do we tell students what to study and how to study, we also explain the subjects, compile and create useful resources on the subject, and control vast stores of authoritative books, videos, and CDs on almost every academic discipline. Finally, we administrate the massive files on all verification results coming out of Kristina “KJ” Zaloum’s rigorous scholastic examinations. Our job lies at the very center of Verity’s core reason; as I said before, the beating heart of the program. This is why Charity, KJ and I are closely protected by the thick concrete wall of the second floor. Those pretty faces which inhabit the furnished rooms below provide a pleasant façade to the earnest toil being wrought magnificently along the study corridors above. We three are the throbbing heart, full of verve and vigor and vitality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near the end of July a select contingent of Verity staffers and my sister, Sarah (Clarke), were deployed to a homeschooler conference in Atlanta (Georgia). We were charged with representing Verity (Institute) to people who had not heard of us. As it turned out, I spent most of the time scouting out good curriculum ideas at special sessions and spying on current college marketing strategies by asking tough questions to the representatives in their color-coded booths. Then I stuffed the brochures in a little white baggie to give to Chéri (Anderson). It was a rather fun expedition in all, made even nicer by the graciousness of the Dalrymple family opening their home to us both nights we were in Atlanta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The summer term at Verity passed beneath the looming arrival of the 2010 class and the in-depth orientation we needed to give them. Of course, we were working under bad conditions: time was passing as fast as usual. Between park night, birthday parties, weekly lunches out with Sarah, a tennis tournament, and a day trip to the amazing Creation Museum in Kentucky, all the work got done and the Verity staff celebrated by taking a trip to see the Squire Boone Caverns in Kentucky.  Squire was his name, not a title. He was Daniel’s brother and in the caverns we saw the new burial place of his seventeen recovered bones. I assume he had more, but maybe he was part jellyfish. They identified the partial skeleton by the (non-lethal) hatchet hole in his skull. I always say it is useful to have something recognizable with you at all times for other folk’s convenience. For instance, I have a face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point in the story I took a short break to Georgia where I spent a week with my family at Tugaloo State Park. You may think that you are noticing a trend with this Georgia thing, in which case, you are right. Partly from coincidence, partly because it is home, I spent a good bit of the year in Georgia. Tugaloo was a nice place and one day we climbed Curahee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Verity 2010 class students had arrived for a week of spiritual introspection while I was lounging and hiking with my family. They returned to the Indianapolis campus about the same time I did and we together launched into an intense week of Biblical worldview training, explanations of the Verity system, and some good study ideas. Few people realize the importance of understanding the processes by which learning happens. Frankly, the osmosis joke is getting pretty tired. Biology students are apt to dream about having the material seep into their brain during night from a book under the pillow. Personally, I shudder to think of my skull being able to just absorb whatever happens to be lying close by: that ability sounds rank with disease and pollution. Also, I think they are forgetting that osmosis happens with water and a semi-permeable membrane. Unless you want to sleep with a book made entirely of water, assuming that is possible, then I motion that we let that joke die. Then week was not entirely spent on such important issues, I also made to the Indianapolis Symphony to see Joshua Bell play his violin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the fall I worked hard and played soccer and involved myself in the many activities happing around the school. The road trip to Chicago to drop off the music students with Dr. Kincaid was fun.  Josh Ingersoll, my roommate and the music program advisor, and I had the unique opportunity of standing above the center of a four-lane highway. Not every day do I get to sip a McDonalds sweet tea and watch semis filled with who knows what whiz beneath me. In fact, it has only happened once. My family came up to Indy on a visit one weekend. I had fun giving them a tour of Verity and Monument Circle. There is nothing like sitting on the steps of the monument while eating an ice cream from the Chocolate Café and watching the motorcycles ride the circle. I am not saying that it is the pinnacle of human experience; it just stands unique as an evening’s entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last month and a half of the fall term was dead serious for me. I prepared for the Humanities and English Composition classes I was teaching. Then I taught them. The study of Humanities is a very important since it contains the sum of human artistic expression throughout the ages. Of course, my class was somewhat narrower, focusing only on western traditions and highlighting only the most important masters and masterpieces. Still, a conversant knowledge of the arts and literature is vital for any cultured person, if they want to be cultured. Similarly crucial for all educated people is the ability to frame thoughts clearly and attractively in text. A well-written person is indispensable for many good jobs, and is certainly more effective in persuasion both now and beyond the grave than someone whose letters suffer in content, organization, grammar, and creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finishing the school year with that flourish of activity, I made my way back to Georgia for the holidays, or precisely those days between November 17th and January 3rd. It is a strange marvel of the human body that it can embrace fatigue and excitement and toil piled endlessly after each other for weeks on end with scarcely a whimper. But give that same body one days rest following the marathon and it will respond with all manner of illness and coughing and nasal issues that can last for up to a fortnight without remedy. Especially if that body is the one I wear. I recovered shortly after Thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I filled my holiday break with reading, studying, shopping, and visits to and from friends. The Reckner family made a weekend visit in November and we played airsoft and some Verity folks that live across the line in Alabama stayed overnight in December and we played paintball. The entire family went north to Kentucky for Christmas with the Reckners. We kept our tradition of having a large country dance on Christmas Eve and broke the tradition of throwing up all day Christmas. It was a beautiful time and there was only one engagement. Actually, it was the only one we were expecting, but it was nice. I enjoyed seeing Bryce Reckner again and this spring I look forward to meeting Bryce II.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I closed the chapter on 2008, I quietly thanked God for His faithfulness and grace to me. A year which started out completely blank and unknown quickly unfolded into a marvelously pleasant journey. I began the year searching for His will and I never had a doubt as to His leading. Those who seek Him will surely find Him. He does not hide from His children. There was never a question that He did not answer, never a fear that He did not calm, and never a trial that He did not give more grace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the future is still uncertain. I am currently unsure of where the path leads beginning in June. Currently, the several options I am considering are so good I wish I could do them all. I guess that is one of those things about stuff like that, if I knew what was going to happen I would just write the 2009 year in review now. But I do not, so I will keep trust God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Books in Review&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed have the light dry style of my year in review. That was partially due to the recent influence of Wodehouse as you can see from my following reading list from 2008. This is probably the shortest yearly reading list I’ve ever had, but it should grow a little as I remember various volumes which slip my mind now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bible – God&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross Examination of Jesus Christ – Randy Singer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dave Barry Slept Here: A Sort Of History of the United States – Dave Barry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dave Barry’s Last Travel Guide You’ll Ever Need – Dave Barry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fair Tax Book – John Linder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The King’s Stilts – Dr. Seuss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Living Abroad in China – Stuart and Barbara Strother&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Man Who Knew Too Much – G. K. Chesterton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Man with Two Left Feet – P. G. Wodehouse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oliver Twist – Charles Dickens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Poison Plot – Lily Bea Jenkins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Principles of Management – John Ogilvie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psmith in the City – P. G. Wodehouse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding Business – Nichols and McHugh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What Every American Needs to Know About the Qur’an – William Federer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When the Frost is on the Punkin</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/when-the-frost-is-on-the-punkin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/when-the-frost-is-on-the-punkin/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m loving the fall here in Indiana. I can finally understand the scenes so richly described in my favorite poem by Indianapolis&amp;rsquo; own &amp;ldquo;Hoosier Poet.&amp;rdquo; I print below the entire text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;When the Frost is on the Punkin&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James Whitcomb Riley&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WHEN the frost is on the punkin and the fodder&amp;rsquo;s in the shock,&lt;br /&gt;
And you hear the kyouck and gobble of the struttin&amp;rsquo; turkey-cock,&lt;br /&gt;
And the clackin&amp;rsquo; of the guineys, and the cluckin&amp;rsquo; of the hens,&lt;br /&gt;
And the rooster&amp;rsquo;s hallylooyer as he tiptoes on the fence;&lt;br /&gt;
O, it&amp;rsquo;s then the time a feller is a-feelin&amp;rsquo; at his best,&lt;br /&gt;
With the risin&amp;rsquo; sun to greet him from a night of peaceful rest,&lt;br /&gt;
As he leaves the house, bareheaded, and goes out to feed the stock,&lt;br /&gt;
When the frost is on the punkin and the fodder&amp;rsquo;s in the shock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;s something kindo&amp;rsquo; harty-like about the atmusfere&lt;br /&gt;
When the heat of summer&amp;rsquo;s over and the coolin&amp;rsquo; fall is here—&lt;br /&gt;
Of course we miss the flowers, and the blossoms on the trees,&lt;br /&gt;
And the mumble of the hummin&amp;rsquo;-birds and buzzin&amp;rsquo; of the bees;&lt;br /&gt;
But the air&amp;rsquo;s so appetizin&amp;rsquo;; and the landscape through the haze&lt;br /&gt;
Of a crisp and sunny morning of the airly autumn days&lt;br /&gt;
Is a pictur&amp;rsquo; that no painter has the colorin&amp;rsquo; to mock—&lt;br /&gt;
When the frost is on the punkin and the fodder&amp;rsquo;s in the shock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The husky, rusty russel of the tossels of the corn,&lt;br /&gt;
And the raspin&amp;rsquo; of the tangled leaves as golden as the morn;&lt;br /&gt;
The stubble in the furries—kindo&amp;rsquo; lonesome-like, but still&lt;br /&gt;
A-preachin&amp;rsquo; sermuns to us of the barns they growed to fill;&lt;br /&gt;
The strawstack in the medder, and the reaper in the shed;&lt;br /&gt;
The hosses in theyr stalls below—the clover overhead!—&lt;br /&gt;
O, it sets my hart a-clickin&amp;rsquo; like the tickin&amp;rsquo; of a clock,&lt;br /&gt;
When the frost is on the punkin and the fodder&amp;rsquo;s in the shock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then your apples all is gethered, and the ones a feller keeps&lt;br /&gt;
Is poured around the cellar-floor in red and yaller heaps;&lt;br /&gt;
And your cider-makin&amp;rsquo;s over, and your wimmern-folks is through&lt;br /&gt;
With theyr mince and apple-butter, and theyr souse and sausage too!&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to tell it—but ef such a thing could be&lt;br /&gt;
As the angels wantin&amp;rsquo; boardin&amp;rsquo;, and they&amp;rsquo;d call around on me—&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;d want to &amp;lsquo;commodate &amp;lsquo;em—all the whole-indurin&amp;rsquo; flock—&lt;br /&gt;
When the frost is on the punkin and the fodder&amp;rsquo;s in the shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Source Code for Windows 2000</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/source-code-windows-2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/source-code-windows-2000/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a hilarious bit of joke code I found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/* Source Code Windows 2000 */
#include &amp;quot;win31.h&amp;quot;
#include &amp;quot;win95.h&amp;quot;
#include &amp;quot;win98.h&amp;quot;
#include &amp;quot;workst~1.h&amp;quot;
#include &amp;quot;evenmore.h&amp;quot;
#include &amp;quot;oldstuff.h&amp;quot;
#include &amp;quot;billrulz.h&amp;quot;
#include &amp;quot;mindsweeper.h&amp;quot;
#include &amp;quot;backdoor.h&amp;quot;
#define INSTALL = HARD
char make_prog_look_big(16000000);
void main()
{
  while(!CRASHED)
  {
    display_copyright_message();
    display_bill_rules_message();
    do_nothing_loop();
    if (first_time_installation)
      {
      make_100_megabyte_swapfile();
      do_nothing_loop();
      totally_screw_up_HPFS_file_system();
      search_and_destroy_the_rest_of-OS2();
      make_futile_attempt_to_damage_Linux();
      disable_Netscape();
      disable_RealPlayer();
      disable_Lotus_Products();
      hang_system();
      } //if
    write_something(anything);
    display_copyright_message();
    do_nothing_loop();
    do_some_stuff();
    if (still_not_crashed)
    {
    display_copyright_message();
    do_nothing_loop();
    basically_run_windows_31();
    do_nothing_loop();
    } // if
  } //while
  if (detect_cache())
    disable_cache();
  if (fast_cpu())
    {
    set_wait_states(lots);
    set_mouse(speed,very_slow);
    set_mouse(action,jumpy);
    set_mouse(reaction,sometimes);
    } //if
  /* printf(&amp;quot;Welcome to Windows 3.1&amp;quot;);    */
  /* printf(&amp;quot;Welcome to Windows 3.11&amp;quot;);   */
  /* printf(&amp;quot;Welcome to Windows 95&amp;quot;);     */
  /* printf(&amp;quot;Welcome to Windows NT 3.0&amp;quot;); */
  /* printf(&amp;quot;Welcome to Windows 98&amp;quot;);     */
  /* printf(&amp;quot;Welcome to Windows NT 4.0&amp;quot;); */
  printf(&amp;quot;Welcome to Windows 2000&amp;quot;);
  if (system_ok())
    crash(to_dos_prompt)
  else
    system_memory = open(&amp;quot;a:\swp0001.swp&amp;quot;,O_CREATE);
  while(something)
    {
    sleep(5);
    get_user_input();
    sleep(5);
    act_on_user_input();
    sleep(5);
    } // while
  create_general_protection_fault();
} // main
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Last Visit to RCI</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/my-last-visit-to-rci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/my-last-visit-to-rci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m wandering around in the RCI. I never though this would happen again. Memories of past days are coming back and it&amp;rsquo;s been very nostalgic and fun. Volleyball in the ball room was just like I alway remember it, with the Team of Destiny chairs set up behind the nets. My old room 2628 is still set up the way JRod, Cameron and I left it, even though most other rooms are changed a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slept in Classroom 1 on the third floor. The only sign that Verity was even here are two office name tags that have never been removed from the wall. The lower dining room has now been set up like a living room with sofas and curtains: it&amp;rsquo;s very nice. I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in the lobby in front of the fireplace as I type this, in about the same spot that I received my Verity diploma about 2 and a half years ago. I can see the fishpond and the Mayor&amp;rsquo;s room where I taught Harmony to the &amp;lsquo;07ers and the front desk and the grand piano that Isaiah always used to play. I&amp;rsquo;m headed out now to go hear the huge organ at the First Presbyterian Church again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will never forget this place, or thing things I did here, or the people I knew here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday February 2, 2008</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/saturday-february-2-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/saturday-february-2-2008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am back at Verity now. I&amp;rsquo;ll be here for a while as guest lecturer and assistant to the curriculum developer. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, Verity is now in Indianapolis. So it&amp;rsquo;s odd going back to my school and finding it in an entirely different state. Still this is a nice place and the guys move into the new rooms today. I&amp;rsquo;m in with the staff guys and we get an entire 5 room suite. That&amp;rsquo;s nice. It should be a good run up here. I still haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten a glimpse of my sister - she was at the symphony till late last night.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardy Boys speed reading challenge</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/hardy-boys-speed-reading-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/hardy-boys-speed-reading-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.online-stopwatch.com/large-stopwatch/%20&#34;&gt;http://www.online-stopwatch.com/large-stopwatch/&lt;/a&gt;, I read the Hardy Boys book &lt;em&gt;The Tower Treasure&lt;/em&gt; in 1 hour and 11 minutes and 1 second. That is shorter than the movie would be. This beats my previous (and first) record of 1 hour and 45 minutes, roughly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2007 Year in Review</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/2007-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/2007-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick list of books that I read this year. I know this isn&amp;rsquo;t complete, but it&amp;rsquo;s all the ones either on my desk or remembered for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Christian&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caring People&lt;/em&gt; by Warren W. Wiersbe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gaining Favor with God and Man&lt;/em&gt; by William M. Thayer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Life’s Greatest Lessons&lt;/em&gt; by Hal Urban&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I Don’t Have Enough Faith to Be an Athiest&lt;/em&gt; by Norman Giesler and Frank Turek&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Love and Respect&lt;/em&gt; by Emerson Eggerichs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Four Pillars of a Man’s Heart&lt;/em&gt; by Stu Weber&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Boy Meets Girl&lt;/em&gt; by Joshua Harris&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dare 2 Share&lt;/em&gt; by Greg Stier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;2 Live 4&lt;/em&gt; by Ryan Dobson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New Evidence That Demands a Verdict&lt;/em&gt; by Josh McDowell (it&amp;rsquo;s huge)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mere Christianity&lt;/em&gt; by C. S. Lewis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Secular&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cabbages and Kings&lt;/em&gt; by O. Henry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Monster&lt;/em&gt; by Frank Peretti&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;House&lt;/em&gt; by Frank Peretti and Ted Dekker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dave Barry Slept Here&lt;/em&gt; by Dave Barry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dave Barry&amp;rsquo;s Only Travel Guide You’ll Ever Need&lt;/em&gt; by Dave Barry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Claw Your Way to the Top&lt;/em&gt; by Dave Barry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Complete Father Brown&lt;/em&gt; by G. K. Chesterton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Personal Finance for Dummies&lt;/em&gt; by Eric Tyson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intelligence in War&lt;/em&gt; by John Keegan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;An Inconvenient Book&lt;/em&gt; by Glenn Beck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Treason&lt;/em&gt; by Ann Coulter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slander&lt;/em&gt; by Ann Coulter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Godless&lt;/em&gt; by Ann Coulter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Rights of Man&lt;/em&gt; by Thomas Paine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Web (Tech) News&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.winsupersite.com&#34;&gt;www.winsupersite.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arstechnica.com&#34;&gt;www.arstechnica.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, my friends, is a snapshot of my read this past year, at least the part I can remember tonight. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll add more when I think of them, but don&amp;rsquo;t hold your breath (asphyxiation is bad for your health).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to Andrew</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/listening-to-andrew/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/listening-to-andrew/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andrew and I went to the dump to dispose of our trash. This is what he said on our road home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrew: Deers are used to the sound of cars but they don&amp;rsquo;t like cars. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that funny? Did you know that if you&amp;rsquo;re covered in spices you won&amp;rsquo;t rot? I was just thinking about that because we drove past the cemetery back there: the one with the dead people. In the old days - I don&amp;rsquo;t think they do it anymore - in the old days they used to bury people in the Pharaoh places. You know, those things. They had hallways and were big. And I was thinking: wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be funny today if they buried people in one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan: I think it would be expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrew: I guess so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Tis What Season...?</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/tis-what-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/tis-what-season/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By the way, what season is it anyway? I was at Best Buy last night and I walked over to the table where they were selling the holiday gift cards. I say &amp;ldquo;holiday&amp;rdquo; with purpose. I&amp;rsquo;m not using it as a contraction of holy and day used for Christian celebrations, I&amp;rsquo;m using it as an all-purpose, non-religious term for the 25th of December, or more, Thanksgiving through New Year&amp;rsquo;s Day. (When was the last time you wished someone a happy holiday for July 4th? What about the Late Spring Holiday Season of Mother&amp;rsquo;s Day, Memorial Day, Father&amp;rsquo;s Day and Flag day?) So I&amp;rsquo;m standing at the gift card table and there are four different styles to suit everyone: Happy Kwanzaa, Happy Hanukkah, Love and Holiday (with a bride and a groom on it) and Giving Season with a gift. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t a &amp;ldquo;Christmas&amp;rdquo;, a manger, or a angel to be seen. Not even a serene looking female angel with long flaxen hair and a trumpet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I&amp;rsquo;m saying is that Christmas was a very big thing: God became man. It deserves a big celebration, and now it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even get a mention from corporate people who &amp;lsquo;know.&amp;rsquo; Sometimes it feels like they have taken the Christ out of Christmas and now they are destroying the last remnant of the X in Xmas. But I can still worship the newborn Christ, and that&amp;rsquo;s what I plan to do, whether it&amp;rsquo;s officially endorsed by Best Buy or not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth and Perception</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/truth-and-perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/truth-and-perception/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it amazes me, the incredible arrogance of our intellect. As if our thoughts create reality. There is Truth and then there is Perception. Truth is what it is, but Perception is what we think Truth is. And we think that what we perceive Truth to be is the way Truth really is. Though Truth never changes, Perception does, and the vigilant will quickly realize how transient and impaired our finite grasp of real reality is within ourselves. And thus, before we can discover Truth, we must find unerring Perception. If our feeble attempts at Perception quickly become exposed as theory and opinion, then authority can only be found outside ourself in Knowledge, which is an understanding of Truth. We cannot generate Knowledge. Therefore, we cannot find Truth in its ultimate and purest state: Truth must be given to us. Who will give us Truth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look no farther that the Bible where we find Jesus proclaimed as The Word, the very embodiment of Knowledge. We also see Jesus defining Himself as The Truth. We ask ourself, is this a legitimate claim? The answer is a resounding affirmative since in Genesis we see Jesus making everything. God was, and then He created. God made reality and truth and therefore is intimately qualified to act as the supreme interpreter. Just as truth is unusable without being perceived and perception is dangerous unless it accurately reflects truth, so correct understanding is able to unlock the mysteries of life and allow us to live purposefully and meaningfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, we must endeavor to lay aside our own thinking and the philosophies of man which surround us and immerse ourselves in the knowing instructions of our Creator contained in the Bible. What a marvelous Book, with principles that even a child can live by and the answers to mysteries that have confounded geniuses for millennia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to believe something, I don&amp;rsquo;t need it to be easy or fair or even common-sensical, I just need it to be true, because my life depends on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday December 6, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/thursday-december-6-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/thursday-december-6-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I made it back to Georgia about 24 hours ago. Sarah and I left Arizona a week ago Thursday and 2001 miles, 7 days, and 11 states later we made it home. Of course, you may be thinking that a week is a long time for such a drive and you&amp;rsquo;re right. We stopped for a day in Kansas for Mama Shoe&amp;rsquo;s memorial service and two days in Kentucky visiting the Reckner&amp;rsquo;s. So it was a leisurely trip. The last day was the most eventful. We were hardly 5 miles from the Reckner&amp;rsquo;s when the rear passenger tire totally disintegrated. We had to unload the entire trunk to get the jack and the spare out and that when I discovered that the included jack was totally useless for changing the rear tire. Fortunately Mr. Reckner had a bottle jack and was able to help me get changed to limp into town and get a new tire. It took a while so we didn&amp;rsquo;t head for home until mid-afternoon. But we&amp;rsquo;re back and it&amp;rsquo;s great to be with family again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the next step, whatever it is. All this has kept me crushingly busy so I&amp;rsquo;ll probably take a short breather and then start pursuing my future again with anticipation. There are these little dreams we all have, and maybe some of mine will start to come true. By &amp;ldquo;little&amp;rdquo; dreams, I mean those impossibly magnificient ideas that we harbor so close to our soul until they become a living part of us. Life isn&amp;rsquo;t always easy, but it&amp;rsquo;s terribly exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is My Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/this-is-my-thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/this-is-my-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been blessed with a good life. Throughout my journey, God has never ceased to shower all manner of sweet providence along my way. Many good things have happened to me that I have had no control over, from the dynamic family I was placed in to the amazing resilience of my fearfully made person.  And then, in love, God gently and surely called me to be His own and bought me with his blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My God has lead my steps, even when I was not consciously aware of His work. At other times when I cried for guidance and direction as I anxiously awaited looming deadlines and decisions, He has never failed to reveal His perfect and often unexpected will even if it may appear to be only at the last minute. Because of this long history of faithfulness to me, I can confidently approach the future with peace that it is in His hands. My present state of uncertainty has only worked to make me more excited about the possibilities ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My new adventure started on Monday, November the 12ᵗʰ.  I had just arrived home the weekend before from a week of work in Vancouver, BC, Canada manufacturing the last batch of MannaFlax with the supplies at our Surrey warehouse, and then packaging all the equipment and machinery for shipment back to Payson so we setup and continue operation in the states. This trip was very significant since it marked the end of the development cycle on the new health supplement we were making as we entered the production and commercial phase and started to sell product. I went to work on Monday expecting to start an endless (and hopefully increasing) cycle of making and selling. Instead, God had other plans. The Payson plant manager came to me and said that due to my efficient work effort in helping create MannaFlax and also some unrelated company financial difficulties I had worked myself out of a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expected to feel hurt or sad or disappointed, instead I felt happy and excited. When I started this job 17 months ago, I did it because God was clearly in it. Though I loved the job, and the interesting work, and fun coworkers, I always realized that the remote location was a very big drawback. Many times during my stay in Payson I’ve wanted to move so I could be closer to family and friends, but especially family. As hard as it was at times, I could never bring myself to leave because I was too comfortable to move and because I believed the Lord still wanted me here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For personal reasons, my week in Vancouver was very hard, a situation multiplied by the international factor prohibiting any phone calls to my family. I did a lot of thinking that week about packing up and moving on, even though I knew in my heart that I wouldn’t unless God clearly showed me I was to leave. Then unexpectedly on that Monday morning, God showed me the next step in His will.  And the event that I always viewed as a terrible thing made me smile because I knew my God cared for me and was making it easy for me to follow Him into the next adventure. It’s a funny thing about God, he likes to do things “backwards” but perfectly: first = last, humble = exalted, poor = rich, downsized = excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I finished up my work with the company and “put my affairs in order.” Then I flew out east for an absolute humdinger of a whirlwind tour with my family for Thanksgiving. Saying it was a great time would be an understatement. I am now back in Payson for a last few days packing up my few things in preparation to move home. My sister Sarah is flying out here tomorrow morning and we’ll be driving my Grandma Car back home. That should be a lot of fun. The church youth group is having a “We’re Mad at You for Leaving” party Wednesday night. Of all the things I’ll miss here in Arizona, by far the biggest will be the wonderful church family I have had the privilege of worshiping with this last year and some months. Ponderosa Baptist is a church where the majority of the people are doing ministry with the church is some way: it is a church that blows the 80-20 rule out of the water. It’s a beautiful thing to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now some people may think that this excursion to Payson has been a dead end that wasted many valuable months. In fact I am surprised that I don’t feel a little like that, but I find that I cannot be regretful in light of the many important things I’ve learned here. This post is already too long to list them all, and I’m sure I would forget some. I’m not sure if Payson, as a geographical location was so important, but the isolation from family and former friends, the unique mix of coworkers and new friends, and the special opportunities and challenges combined to make this “Payson Experience” a significant and necessary step in my personal growth. And let’s face it: Payson is a pretty nice place to live with one of the best climates I’ve ever experienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I move ahead. I must confess I really don’t know what I’ll be doing next, other than spending a nice December with my family. January is an open slate and rather than worry about it, I’ll trust God that He will fill in the details in His way in His time. He’s done it before and He can do it again. Frankly, I’m pretty excited to see what God does! This is my Thanksgiving, and God is the hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday November 21, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/wednesday-november-21-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/wednesday-november-21-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The wedding was amazing. I have spent the last few days at home and now we&amp;rsquo;re all headed up to North Carolina for Thanksgiving. Here&amp;rsquo;s wishing you all a happy Thanksgiving and a grateful heart.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday November 14, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/wednesday-november-14-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/wednesday-november-14-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m headed east! I&amp;rsquo;m spending a day at Verity before heading down to my good friend Bryce&amp;rsquo;s wedding where I&amp;rsquo;ll be the best man. Then I spend the whole following week and Thanksgiving with my family. This is going to be fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>