<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/tags/milestone/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
    <copyright>© 2014 Ryan Clarke</copyright>
    <updated>Fri, 17 Aug 2007 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday August 17, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/friday-august-17-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/friday-august-17-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m now halfway through this day, this day that I am 22½ years old. Woohoo for me!
Today is the start of the World&amp;rsquo;s Oldest Continuous Rodeo here in Payson. Actually, it&amp;rsquo;s the World&amp;rsquo;s Oldest Rodeo too, but Prescott, AZ copywrited that title (unjustly). So yes, our rodeo is older AND has been held every year. Take THAT, Prescott!
By the way, did you know that the CD (Compact Disk) turned 25 today. 25!?!?! The first one came off the production line this date in 1982. Since that time over 200 billion have been made. I think that 150 billion of them were probably those ever-present AOL signup disks. So CDs are officially 2½ years older than me.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday June 7, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/thursday-june-7-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/thursday-june-7-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And so I started my second year as a contributing member of society (yikes, that sounded Marxist). The second year started much more buoyantly than year one ended. Good news.
On a personal note: what if you woke up one morning and found that you had actually dropped off the face of the planet. For real.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday June 6, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/wednesday-june-6-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/wednesday-june-6-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And so, I finished my first year of work. I should have been a happy day as not only was it a big milestone but I was covered in sugar almost the entire afternoon. But for some reason I had one of my lowest days in months. I was overwhelmed with a sense of futility (I hate it when that happens). Mom says it&amp;rsquo;s good though, because it proves that I&amp;rsquo;m real. Haha, I had to laugh. I guess I am happy almost all the time, and I don&amp;rsquo;t let bad situations steal my joy. But occasionally that little unrest in my soul that pushes me to dream bigger things breaks loose and points a haughty finger at the pleasant niche I&amp;rsquo;ve carved alone here in Arizona. And I wish for more.
I feel better now because I&amp;rsquo;m realizing I&amp;rsquo;ve done more this last year than go to work 244 days. I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, I&amp;rsquo;ve matured, and I&amp;rsquo;ve proven myself, in some small way, to myself. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m closer to the goal.
On a personal note: I saw myself in the mirror this morning. Again.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday May 10, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/thursday-may-10-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/thursday-may-10-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A milestone.
Literally.
Well, minus the stone.
My car passed 90,009 miles today.
It deserves an oil change, just for that.
God sure picked me a good car.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

