<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Health on Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/tags/health/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fable of Simon McDarpet</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/post/the-fable-of-simon-mcdarpet</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/post/the-fable-of-simon-mcdarpet</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I give you the fable of Simon McDarpet,&lt;br /&gt;
A boy, it would seem, with a hatred for carpet;&lt;br /&gt;
And tables, of course, and most anything wooden&lt;br /&gt;
And things that get hurt when you act like you shouldn’t,&lt;br /&gt;
And all sorts of rugs, also windows and doors.&lt;br /&gt;
But your guess would be right if you singled out floors.&lt;br /&gt;
You’d be right on the money—the wad that was spent—&lt;br /&gt;
On repairing the issues he could have prevent-&lt;br /&gt;
ed because of the sloshing of liquids he did,&lt;br /&gt;
All because he refused to seal drinks with a lid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And don’t get me started on all of the chow&lt;br /&gt;
That was strewn down the hall in the wake of that cow.&lt;br /&gt;
Steaming heaps of lasagna and well-buttered biscuits,&lt;br /&gt;
Potatoes with herbs that were creamed with a wisk—it’s&lt;br /&gt;
A shame—and I know of the groans in my belly,&lt;br /&gt;
Surveying the wasted baked oatmeal and jelly.&lt;br /&gt;
However the groans that were felt in the gut&lt;br /&gt;
Of another man spying the path to the mutt&lt;br /&gt;
(Like a humanoid snail or a monstrous slug&lt;br /&gt;
Who was leaving a trail of wet smears on the rug);&lt;br /&gt;
These were groans that could make a man wither in fear&lt;br /&gt;
And concurrently make that same man shed a tear,&lt;br /&gt;
As poor Curtis would go fetch the tools of his trade,&lt;br /&gt;
For the treasure of kingdoms could scarcely have paid&lt;br /&gt;
For the hours he spent grimly cleaning the carpet&lt;br /&gt;
Of stains that were left by that Simon McDarpet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you’ll remember, dear cleanliness lover,&lt;br /&gt;
To never move food without using a cover.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday May 8, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/tuesday-may-8-2007</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/tuesday-may-8-2007</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I got back from my run, my sweat smelled like bleach. Have I been cleaning too much at work?
Now to learn some Chinese&amp;hellip;
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>