<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Olds on Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/old/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Curse of a Dream Job</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/the-curse-of-a-dream-job</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/the-curse-of-a-dream-job</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanclarke.net/post/the-curse-of-a-dream-job/cursedreamjob/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ryanclarke.net/wp-content/uploads/CurseDreamJob.png&#34; alt=&#34;Funny toddler who fell asleep while playing with toys&#34; title=&#34;Tired of toys&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; No sooner does a person get a job they love then it starts to destroy them. Jesus said His burden is easy, and it is a good thing, because the ones we give ourselves rarely are. Good employees think that they have to do their best at work. And then the work expands, bringing discouragement or exhaustion. The true standard: good employees should do their best in the time they are given. Companies can not own slaves. If they are buying eight hours each day, give them an honest eight. Not ten. Have something else to do with those other hours, besides sleep: develop good hobbies, invest in family. Strong family relationships take time and can not be patched together as easily as work projects. A good employee who has things to look forward to after work will find that he remains a good employee and has a more fulfilling life. Avoid burnout.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When the Frost is on the Punkin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/when-the-frost-is-on-the-punkin</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/when-the-frost-is-on-the-punkin</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m loving the fall here in Indiana. I can finally understand the scenes so richly described in my favorite poem by Indianapolis&amp;rsquo; own &amp;ldquo;Hoosier Poet.&amp;rdquo; I print below the entire text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;When the Frost is on the Punkin&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James Whitcomb Riley&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WHEN the frost is on the punkin and the fodder&amp;rsquo;s in the shock,&lt;br /&gt;
And you hear the kyouck and gobble of the struttin&amp;rsquo; turkey-cock,&lt;br /&gt;
And the clackin&amp;rsquo; of the guineys, and the cluckin&amp;rsquo; of the hens,&lt;br /&gt;
And the rooster&amp;rsquo;s hallylooyer as he tiptoes on the fence;&lt;br /&gt;
O, it&amp;rsquo;s then the time a feller is a-feelin&amp;rsquo; at his best,&lt;br /&gt;
With the risin&amp;rsquo; sun to greet him from a night of peaceful rest,&lt;br /&gt;
As he leaves the house, bareheaded, and goes out to feed the stock,&lt;br /&gt;
When the frost is on the punkin and the fodder&amp;rsquo;s in the shock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;s something kindo&amp;rsquo; harty-like about the atmusfere&lt;br /&gt;
When the heat of summer&amp;rsquo;s over and the coolin&amp;rsquo; fall is here—&lt;br /&gt;
Of course we miss the flowers, and the blossoms on the trees,&lt;br /&gt;
And the mumble of the hummin&amp;rsquo;-birds and buzzin&amp;rsquo; of the bees;&lt;br /&gt;
But the air&amp;rsquo;s so appetizin&amp;rsquo;; and the landscape through the haze&lt;br /&gt;
Of a crisp and sunny morning of the airly autumn days&lt;br /&gt;
Is a pictur&amp;rsquo; that no painter has the colorin&amp;rsquo; to mock—&lt;br /&gt;
When the frost is on the punkin and the fodder&amp;rsquo;s in the shock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The husky, rusty russel of the tossels of the corn,&lt;br /&gt;
And the raspin&amp;rsquo; of the tangled leaves as golden as the morn;&lt;br /&gt;
The stubble in the furries—kindo&amp;rsquo; lonesome-like, but still&lt;br /&gt;
A-preachin&amp;rsquo; sermuns to us of the barns they growed to fill;&lt;br /&gt;
The strawstack in the medder, and the reaper in the shed;&lt;br /&gt;
The hosses in theyr stalls below—the clover overhead!—&lt;br /&gt;
O, it sets my hart a-clickin&amp;rsquo; like the tickin&amp;rsquo; of a clock,&lt;br /&gt;
When the frost is on the punkin and the fodder&amp;rsquo;s in the shock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then your apples all is gethered, and the ones a feller keeps&lt;br /&gt;
Is poured around the cellar-floor in red and yaller heaps;&lt;br /&gt;
And your cider-makin&amp;rsquo;s over, and your wimmern-folks is through&lt;br /&gt;
With theyr mince and apple-butter, and theyr souse and sausage too!&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to tell it—but ef such a thing could be&lt;br /&gt;
As the angels wantin&amp;rsquo; boardin&amp;rsquo;, and they&amp;rsquo;d call around on me—&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;d want to &amp;lsquo;commodate &amp;lsquo;em—all the whole-indurin&amp;rsquo; flock—&lt;br /&gt;
When the frost is on the punkin and the fodder&amp;rsquo;s in the shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Source Code for Windows 2000</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/source-code-windows-2000</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/source-code-windows-2000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a hilarious bit of joke code I found.
/* Source Code Windows 2000 */
#include &amp;ldquo;win31.h&amp;rdquo;
#include &amp;ldquo;win95.h&amp;rdquo;
#include &amp;ldquo;win98.h&amp;rdquo;
#include &amp;ldquo;workst~1.h&amp;rdquo;
#include &amp;ldquo;evenmore.h&amp;rdquo;
#include &amp;ldquo;oldstuff.h&amp;rdquo;
#include &amp;ldquo;billrulz.h&amp;rdquo;
#include &amp;ldquo;mindsweeper.h&amp;rdquo;
#include &amp;ldquo;backdoor.h&amp;rdquo;
#define INSTALL = HARD
char make_prog_look_big(16000000);
void main()
{
  while(!CRASHED)
  {
    display_copyright_message();
    display_bill_rules_message();
    do_nothing_loop();
    if (first_time_installation)
      {
      make_100_megabyte_swapfile();
      do_nothing_loop();
      totally_screw_up_HPFS_file_system();
      search_and_destroy_the_rest_of-OS2();
      make_futile_attempt_to_damage_Linux();
      disable_Netscape();
      disable_RealPlayer();
      disable_Lotus_Products();
      hang_system();
      } //if
    write_something(anything);
    display_copyright_message();
    do_nothing_loop();
    do_some_stuff();
    if (still_not_crashed)
    {
    display_copyright_message();
    do_nothing_loop();
    basically_run_windows_31();
    do_nothing_loop();
    } // if
  } //while
  if (detect_cache())
    disable_cache();
  if (fast_cpu())
    {
    set_wait_states(lots);
    set_mouse(speed,very_slow);
    set_mouse(action,jumpy);
    set_mouse(reaction,sometimes);
    } //if
  /* printf(&amp;ldquo;Welcome to Windows 3.1&amp;rdquo;);    */
  /* printf(&amp;ldquo;Welcome to Windows 3.11&amp;rdquo;);   */
  /* printf(&amp;ldquo;Welcome to Windows 95&amp;rdquo;);     */
  /* printf(&amp;ldquo;Welcome to Windows NT 3.0&amp;rdquo;); */
  /* printf(&amp;ldquo;Welcome to Windows 98&amp;rdquo;);     */
  /* printf(&amp;ldquo;Welcome to Windows NT 4.0&amp;rdquo;); */
  printf(&amp;ldquo;Welcome to Windows 2000&amp;rdquo;);
  if (system_ok())
    crash(to_dos_prompt)
  else
    system_memory = open(&amp;ldquo;a:\swp0001.swp&amp;rdquo;,O_CREATE);
  while(something)
    {
    sleep(5);
    get_user_input();
    sleep(5);
    act_on_user_input();
    sleep(5);
    } // while
  create_general_protection_fault();
} // main
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Last Visit to RCI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/my-last-visit-to-rci</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/my-last-visit-to-rci</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m wandering around in the RCI. I never though this would happen again. Memories of past days are coming back and it&amp;rsquo;s been very nostalgic and fun. Volleyball in the ball room was just like I alway remember it, with the Team of Destiny chairs set up behind the nets. My old room 2628 is still set up the way JRod, Cameron and I left it, even though most other rooms are changed a lot.  I slept in Classroom 1 on the third floor. The only sign that Verity was even here are two office name tags that have never been removed from the wall. The lower dining room has now been set up like a living room with sofas and curtains: it&amp;rsquo;s very nice. I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in the lobby in front of the fireplace as I type this, in about the same spot that I received my Verity diploma about 2 and a half years ago. I can see the fishpond and the Mayor&amp;rsquo;s room where I taught Harmony to the &amp;lsquo;07ers and the front desk and the grand piano that Isaiah always used to play. I&amp;rsquo;m headed out now to go hear the huge organ at the First Presbyterian Church again.
I will never forget this place, or thing things I did here, or the people I knew here.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday February 2, 2008</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/saturday-february-2-2008</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/saturday-february-2-2008</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am back at Verity now. I&amp;rsquo;ll be here for a while as guest lecturer and assistant to the curriculum developer. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, Verity is now in Indianapolis. So it&amp;rsquo;s odd going back to my school and finding it in an entirely different state. Still this is a nice place and the guys move into the new rooms today. I&amp;rsquo;m in with the staff guys and we get an entire 5 room suite. That&amp;rsquo;s nice. It should be a good run up here. I still haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten a glimpse of my sister - she was at the symphony till late last night.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday January 8, 2008</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/tuesday-january-8-2008</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/tuesday-january-8-2008</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.online-stopwatch.com/large-stopwatch/%20&#34;&gt;http://www.online-stopwatch.com/large-stopwatch/&lt;/a&gt;, I read the Hardy Boys book The Tower Treasure in 1 hour and 11 minutes and 1 second. That is shorter than the movie would be. This beats my previous (and first) record of 1 hour and 45 minutes, roughly.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2007 Year in Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/2007-year-in-review</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/2007-year-in-review</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick list of books that I read this year. I know this isn&amp;rsquo;t complete, but it&amp;rsquo;s all the ones either on my desk or remembered for some reason.
 - Christian
Caring People by Warren W. Wiersbe
Gaining Favor with God and Man by William M. Thayer
Life’s Greatest Lessons by Hal Urban
I Don’t Have Enough Faith to Be an Athiest by Norman Giesler and Frank Turek
Love and Respect by Emerson Eggerichs
Four Pillars of a Man’s Heart by Stu Weber
Boy Meets Girl by Joshua Harris
Dare 2 Share by Greg Stier
2 Live 4 by Ryan Dobson
The New Evidence That Demands a Verdict by Josh McDowell (it&amp;rsquo;s huge)
Mere Christianity by C. S. Lewis
 - Secular
Cabbages and Kings by O. Henry
Monster by Frank Peretti
House by Frank Peretti and Ted Dekker
Dave Barry Slept Here by Dave Barry
Dave Barry&amp;rsquo;s Only Travel Guide You’ll Ever Need by Dave Barry
Claw Your Way to the Top by Dave Barry
The Complete Father Brown by G. K. Chesterton
Personal Finance for Dummies by Eric Tyson
Intelligence in War by John Keegan
An Inconvenient Book by Glenn Beck
Treason by Ann Coulter
Slander by Ann Coulter
Godless by Ann Coulter
The Rights of Man by Thomas Paine
 - Web (Tech) News
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.winsupersite.com&#34;&gt;www.winsupersite.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arstechnica.com&#34;&gt;www.arstechnica.com&lt;/a&gt;
And that, my friends, is a snapshot of my read this past year, at least the part I can remember tonight. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll add more when I think of them, but don&amp;rsquo;t hold your breath (asphyxiation is bad for your health).
Ryan
By the way, I have a new Verizon cell number. Don&amp;rsquo;t call my old phone anymore.
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to Andrew</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/listening-to-andrew</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/listening-to-andrew</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andrew and I went to the dump to dispose of our trash. This is what he said on our road home.
Andrew: &amp;ldquo;Deers are used to the sound of cars but they don&amp;rsquo;t like cars. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that funny? Did you know that if you&amp;rsquo;re covered in spices you won&amp;rsquo;t rot? I was just thinking about that because we drove past the cemetery back there: the one with the dead people. In the old days - I don&amp;rsquo;t think they do it anymore - in the old days they used to bury people in the Pharaoh places. You know, those things. They had hallways and were big. And I was thinking: wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be funny today if they buried people in one?&amp;rdquo;
Ryan: I think it would be expensive.
Andrew: I guess so.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Tis What Season...?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/tis-what-season</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/tis-what-season</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By the way, what season is it anyway? I was at Best Buy last night and I walked over to the table where they were selling the holiday gift cards. I say &amp;ldquo;holiday&amp;rdquo; with purpose. I&amp;rsquo;m not using it as a contraction of holy and day used for Christian celebrations, I&amp;rsquo;m using it as an all-purpose, non-religious term for the 25th of December, or more, Thanksgiving through New Year&amp;rsquo;s Day. (When was the last time you wished someone a happy holiday for July 4th? What about the Late Spring Holiday Season of Mother&amp;rsquo;s Day, Memorial Day, Father&amp;rsquo;s Day and Flag day?) So I&amp;rsquo;m standing at the gift card table and there are four different styles to suit everyone: Happy Kwanzaa, Happy Hanukkah, Love and Holiday (with a bride and a groom on it) and Giving Season with a gift. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t a &amp;ldquo;Christmas&amp;rdquo;, a manger, or a angel to be seen. Not even a serene looking female angel with long flaxen hair and a trumpet.
All I&amp;rsquo;m saying is that Christmas was a very big thing: God became man. It deserves a big celebration, and now it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even get a mention from corporate people who &amp;lsquo;know.&amp;rsquo; Sometimes it feels like they have taken the Christ out of Christmas and now they are destroying the last remnant of the X in Xmas. But I can still worship the newborn Christ, and that&amp;rsquo;s what I plan to do, whether it&amp;rsquo;s officially endorsed by Best Buy or not.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth and Perception</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/truth-and-perception</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/truth-and-perception</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it amazes me, the incredible arrogance of our intellect. As if our thoughts create reality. There is Truth and then there is Perception. Truth is what it is, but Perception is what we think Truth is. And we think that what we perceive Truth to be is the way Truth really is. Though Truth never changes, Perception does, and the vigilant will quickly realize how transient and impaired our finite grasp of real reality is within ourselves. And thus, before we can discover Truth, we must find unerring Perception. If our feeble attempts at Perception quickly become exposed as theory and opinion, then authority can only be found outside ourself in Knowledge, which is an understanding of Truth. We cannot generate Knowledge. Therefore, we cannot find Truth in its ultimate and purest state: Truth must be given to us. Who will give us Truth?
We look no farther that the Bible where we find Jesus proclaimed as The Word, the very embodiment of Knowledge. We also see Jesus defining Himself as The Truth. We ask ourself, is this a legitimate claim? The answer is a resounding affirmative since in Genesis we see Jesus making everything. God was, and then He created. God made reality and truth and therefore is intimately qualified to act as the supreme interpreter. Just as truth is unusable without being perceived and perception is dangerous unless it accurately reflects truth, so correct understanding is able to unlock the mysteries of life and allow us to live purposefully and meaningfully.
And so, we must endeavor to lay aside our own thinking and the philosophies of man which surround us and immerse ourselves in the knowing instructions of our Creator contained in the Bible. What a marvelous Book, with principles that even a child can live by and the answers to mysteries that have confounded geniuses for millennia.
In order to believe something, I don&amp;rsquo;t need it to be easy or fair or even common-sensical, I just need it to be true, because my life depends on it.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday December 6, 2007</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/thursday-december-6-2007</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/thursday-december-6-2007</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I made it back to Georgia about 24 hours ago. Sarah and I left Arizona a week ago Thursday and 2001 miles, 7 days, and 11 states later we made it home. Of course, you may be thinking that a week is a long time for such a drive and you&amp;rsquo;re right. We stopped for a day in Kansas for Mama Shoe&amp;rsquo;s memorial service and two days in Kentucky visiting the Reckner&amp;rsquo;s. So it was a leisurely trip. The last day was the most eventful. We were hardly 5 miles from the Reckner&amp;rsquo;s when the rear passenger tire totally disintegrated. We had to unload the entire trunk to get the jack and the spare out and that when I discovered that the included jack was totally useless for changing the rear tire. Fortunately Mr. Reckner had a bottle jack and was able to help me get changed to limp into town and get a new tire. It took a while so we didn&amp;rsquo;t head for home until mid-afternoon. But we&amp;rsquo;re back and it&amp;rsquo;s great to be with family again.
Now I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the next step, whatever it is. All this has kept me crushingly busy so I&amp;rsquo;ll probably take a short breather and then start pursuing my future again with anticipation. There are these little dreams we all have, and maybe some of mine will start to come true. By &amp;ldquo;little&amp;rdquo; dreams, I mean those impossibly magnificient ideas that we harbor so close to our soul until they become a living part of us. Life isn&amp;rsquo;t always easy, but it&amp;rsquo;s terribly exciting.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is My Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/this-is-my-thanksgiving</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/this-is-my-thanksgiving</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been blessed with a good life. Throughout my journey, God has never ceased to shower all manner of sweet providence along my way. Many good things have happened to me that I have had no control over, from the dynamic family I was placed in to the amazing resilience of my fearfully made person.  And then, in love, God gently and surely called me to be His own and bought me with his blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My God has lead my steps, even when I was not consciously aware of His work. At other times when I cried for guidance and direction as I anxiously awaited looming deadlines and decisions, He has never failed to reveal His perfect and often unexpected will even if it may appear to be only at the last minute. Because of this long history of faithfulness to me, I can confidently approach the future with peace that it is in His hands. My present state of uncertainty has only worked to make me more excited about the possibilities ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My new adventure started on Monday, November the 12&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;.  I had just arrived home the weekend before from a week of work in Vancouver, BC, Canada manufacturing the last batch of MannaFlax with the supplies at our Surrey warehouse, and then packaging all the equipment and machinery for shipment back to Payson so we setup and continue operation in the states. This trip was very significant since it marked the end of the development cycle on the new health supplement we were making as we entered the production and commercial phase and started to sell product. I went to work on Monday expecting to start an endless (and hopefully increasing) cycle of making and selling. Instead, God had other plans. The Payson plant manager came to me and said that due to my efficient work effort in helping create MannaFlax and also some unrelated company financial difficulties I had worked myself out of a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expected to feel hurt or sad or disappointed, instead I felt happy and excited. When I started this job 17 months ago, I did it because God was clearly in it. Though I loved the job, and the interesting work, and fun coworkers, I always realized that the remote location was a very big drawback. Many times during my stay in Payson I’ve wanted to move so I could be closer to family and friends, but especially family. As hard as it was at times, I could never bring myself to leave because I was too comfortable to move and because I believed the Lord still wanted me here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For personal reasons, my week in Vancouver was very hard, a situation multiplied by the international factor prohibiting any phone calls to my family. I did a lot of thinking that week about packing up and moving on, even though I knew in my heart that I wouldn’t unless God clearly showed me I was to leave. Then unexpectedly on that Monday morning, God showed me the next step in His will.  And the event that I always viewed as a terrible thing made me smile because I knew my God cared for me and was making it easy for me to follow Him into the next adventure. It’s a funny thing about God, he likes to do things “backwards” but perfectly: first = last, humble = exalted, poor = rich, downsized = excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I finished up my work with the company and “put my affairs in order.” Then I flew out east for an absolute humdinger of a whirlwind tour with my family for Thanksgiving. Saying it was a great time would be an understatement. I am now back in Payson for a last few days packing up my few things in preparation to move home. My sister Sarah is flying out here tomorrow morning and we’ll be driving my Grandma Car back home. That should be a lot of fun. The church youth group is having a “We’re Mad at You for Leaving” party Wednesday night. Of all the things I’ll miss here in Arizona, by far the biggest will be the wonderful church family I have had the privilege of worshiping with this last year and some months. Ponderosa Baptist is a church where the majority of the people are doing ministry with the church is some way: it is a church that blows the 80-20 rule out of the water. It’s a beautiful thing to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now some people may think that this excursion to Payson has been a dead end that wasted many valuable months. In fact I am surprised that I don’t feel a little like that, but I find that I cannot be regretful in light of the many important things I’ve learned here. This post is already too long to list them all, and I’m sure I would forget some. I’m not sure if Payson, as a geographical location was so important, but the isolation from family and former friends, the unique mix of coworkers and new friends, and the special opportunities and challenges combined to make this “Payson Experience” a significant and necessary step in my personal growth. And let’s face it: Payson is a pretty nice place to live with one of the best climates I’ve ever experienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I move ahead. I must confess I really don’t know what I’ll be doing next, other than spending a nice December with my family. January is an open slate and rather than worry about it, I’ll trust God that He will fill in the details in His way in His time. He’s done it before and He can do it again. Frankly, I’m pretty excited to see what God does! This is my Thanksgiving, and God is the hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday November 21, 2007</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/wednesday-november-21-2007</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/wednesday-november-21-2007</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The wedding was amazing. I have spent the last few days at home and now we&amp;rsquo;re all headed up to North Carolina for Thanksgiving. Here&amp;rsquo;s wishing you all a happy Thanksgiving and a grateful heart.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday November 14, 2007</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/wednesday-november-14-2007</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/wednesday-november-14-2007</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m headed east! I&amp;rsquo;m spending a day at Verity before heading down to my good friend Bryce&amp;rsquo;s wedding where I&amp;rsquo;ll be the best man. Then I spend the whole following week and Thanksgiving with my family. This is going to be fun!
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Situation In Nigeria Seems Pretty Complex</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/old/situation-in-nigeria-seems-pretty-complex</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/old/situation-in-nigeria-seems-pretty-complex</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In The Know: Situation In Nigeria Seems Pretty Complex&lt;/strong&gt;
 Panelists discuss the complicated issues facing Nigeria or Niger in a hilarious spoof on TV &amp;ldquo;experts&amp;rdquo;.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>