<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Writings on Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/categories/writings/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Tips for Maximum Adventure Between 20 and 28</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/6-tips-for-maximum-adventure-between-20-and-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/6-tips-for-maximum-adventure-between-20-and-28/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Advice on Your 20th Birthday from the Perspective of 28 Years&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Friend,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decade which you now commence is fraught with adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was 20, I had lived my entire life in a conservative Christian environment. I was homeschooled, and I earned my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s at Verity Institute. I was a well-learned kid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then I have held 8 job titles at 5 departments of 3 companies in 3 states. I&amp;rsquo;ve been on three international business trips. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken 20 church youth group kids to &lt;a href=&#34;/journal/thursday-october-12-2006/&#34; title=&#34;Magic Mountain in L.A.&#34;&gt;Magic Mountain in L.A.&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been turned down by the girl I loved. I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;/journal/tuesday-september-5-2006/&#34; title=&#34;Surfing in San Diego&#34;&gt;taught Austrian tourists how to surf&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;a href=&#34;/post/this-is-my-thanksgiving/&#34; title=&#34;This is My Thanksgiving&#34;&gt;let go from my job&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten from street vendor carts in Mexico. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in 6 weddings: thrice as groomsman, twice as best man, and once as groom. I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;a href=&#34;/journal/lost-in-the-superstition-mountains/&#34; title=&#34;Lost in the Superstition Mountains&#34;&gt;lost in the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/journal/lost-in-the-superstition-mountains-part-2/&#34; title=&#34;Lost in the Superstition Mountains, Part 2&#34;&gt;desert for two days&lt;/a&gt; waiting for a helicopter to find us. I&amp;rsquo;ve moved 6 times. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a daughter (another one on is the way). I&amp;rsquo;ve laughed a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life goes crazy after you turn twenty: after you leave schooling behind and start doing. There are lots of things to do and lots of things to have happen. Embrace it. Here are a few tips to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Live Temporarily.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We often say &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m just doing this for now&amp;rdquo; we don&amp;rsquo;t think we&amp;rsquo;ll be doing it for &amp;ldquo;the rest of my life.&amp;rdquo; Mortal life by its very nature is not permanent, why dwell on the fact? Live whole-heartedly where ever you are (Psalm 1:3). Who cares if you only &amp;lsquo;plan&amp;rsquo; to be somewhere for 1 year? Get state residency, join a local church, attend a weekly/monthly group of your interest and settle in. You may only be there for a year, but at least you enjoyed it and belonged. If you end up staying for 20 years, at least you didn&amp;rsquo;t wake up 14 years in and realize you have been living like a homeless nomad, minus the change of scenery. Bloom where you are planted, and if you move, start blooming there too. of course, this principle applies to more than just locations, but jobs, etc. too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Avoid Debt.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Debt is slavery: don&amp;rsquo;t go there. If you only spend less than what you have you will never be short of money (although you not have many things). A person in debt cannot live more cheaply because they have obligations they cannot refuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Avoid Responsibility.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responsibility is power. Responsibility is the voluntary acceptance of the important things in life inspiring you to govern your behavior for the good of others. Irresponsibility seems like more freedom, but in the end you&amp;rsquo;ll feel like a kid, and that is not fun when you are an adult. In the end, irresponsibility makes you feel worthless, but responsibility makes you feel needed, important, and satisfied with the good things you create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Be Involved&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good marriage is the best thing in life, and children are a close second. The people around us are what make life fun. Don&amp;rsquo;t do it alone. Don&amp;rsquo;t be stingy with who you like, like as many people as possible. Try to help them, good deeds have a way of making their way around, helping everyone, and often helping you in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;Become Really Good At Something&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you start now, you will be really good at it in 10 years. Pick something you like doing; something that almost makes you feel more energized when you&amp;rsquo;re done with it then when you started, but be sure it&amp;rsquo;s something that someone might pay you for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;Make People Happy.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus said, &amp;ldquo;Sufficient for the day is the evil thereof.&amp;rdquo; (Matt. 6:24) Sometimes the word evil sounds like the simplest description. People live with hearts full of hurt, pain, disappointment (or in the words of &lt;em&gt;Les Miserables&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Life has killed the dream I dreamed&amp;rdquo;): Help ease other&amp;rsquo;s burdens being bring a wee bit o&amp;rsquo; joy where ever possible. A merry heart is so powerful the FDA should regulate it (Prov. 17:22). This decade is &lt;a href=&#34;/post/true-adventure/&#34; title=&#34;True Adventure&#34;&gt;fraught with adventure&lt;/a&gt;. If you live according to my advice, and even more so if you follow the Bible&amp;rsquo;s wisdom, you can experience much adventure. A word of warning, adventure is sometimes difficult, but it&amp;rsquo;s always rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May God&amp;rsquo;s ample blessings comfort you and bring you joy and peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the other side of childhood</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/on-the-other-side-of-childhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/on-the-other-side-of-childhood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the other side of childhood&lt;br /&gt;
When youth’s young bud has grown&lt;br /&gt;
And some flowers it has bloomed produce&lt;br /&gt;
A sprout to call their own,&lt;br /&gt;
May the length of ages not induce&lt;br /&gt;
What often it has wrought&lt;br /&gt;
In accum&amp;rsquo;lative forgetfulness&lt;br /&gt;
And stiffening of thought:&lt;br /&gt;
Don’t ignore the lofty joy and stress&lt;br /&gt;
A juvenile knows,&lt;br /&gt;
But with lavish love fulfill the needs—&lt;br /&gt;
Like rain upon the flower seeds—&lt;br /&gt;
Required by each that grows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other side of childhood&lt;br /&gt;
Recall where once you stood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fable of Simon McDarpet</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/the-fable-of-simon-mcdarpet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/post/the-fable-of-simon-mcdarpet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I give you the fable of Simon McDarpet,&lt;br /&gt;
A boy, it would seem, with a hatred for carpet;&lt;br /&gt;
And tables, of course, and most anything wooden&lt;br /&gt;
And things that get hurt when you act like you shouldn’t,&lt;br /&gt;
And all sorts of rugs, also windows and doors.&lt;br /&gt;
But your guess would be right if you singled out floors.&lt;br /&gt;
You’d be right on the money—the wad that was spent—&lt;br /&gt;
On repairing the issues he could have prevent-&lt;br /&gt;
ed because of the sloshing of liquids he did,&lt;br /&gt;
All because he refused to seal drinks with a lid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And don’t get me started on all of the chow&lt;br /&gt;
That was strewn down the hall in the wake of that cow.&lt;br /&gt;
Steaming heaps of lasagna and well-buttered biscuits,&lt;br /&gt;
Potatoes with herbs that were creamed with a wisk—it’s&lt;br /&gt;
A shame—and I know of the groans in my belly,&lt;br /&gt;
Surveying the wasted baked oatmeal and jelly.&lt;br /&gt;
However the groans that were felt in the gut&lt;br /&gt;
Of another man spying the path to the mutt&lt;br /&gt;
(Like a humanoid snail or a monstrous slug&lt;br /&gt;
Who was leaving a trail of wet smears on the rug);&lt;br /&gt;
These were groans that could make a man wither in fear&lt;br /&gt;
And concurrently make that same man shed a tear,&lt;br /&gt;
As poor Curtis would go fetch the tools of his trade,&lt;br /&gt;
For the treasure of kingdoms could scarcely have paid&lt;br /&gt;
For the hours he spent grimly cleaning the carpet&lt;br /&gt;
Of stains that were left by that Simon McDarpet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you’ll remember, dear cleanliness lover,&lt;br /&gt;
To never move food without using a cover.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>