<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/tags/rules-to-live-by/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
    <copyright>© 2015 Ryan Clarke</copyright>
    <updated>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the other side of childhood</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/on-the-other-side-of-childhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/on-the-other-side-of-childhood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the other side of childhood&lt;br /&gt;
When youth’s young bud has grown&lt;br /&gt;
And some flowers it has bloomed produce&lt;br /&gt;
A sprout to call their own,&lt;br /&gt;
May the length of ages not induce&lt;br /&gt;
What often it has wrought&lt;br /&gt;
In accum&amp;rsquo;lative forgetfulness&lt;br /&gt;
And stiffening of thought:&lt;br /&gt;
Don’t ignore the lofty joy and stress&lt;br /&gt;
A juvenile knows,&lt;br /&gt;
But with lavish love fulfill the needs—&lt;br /&gt;
Like rain upon the flower seeds—&lt;br /&gt;
Required by each that grows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other side of childhood&lt;br /&gt;
Recall where once you stood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Curse of a Dream Job</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/the-curse-of-a-dream-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/the-curse-of-a-dream-job/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No sooner does a person get a job they love then it starts to destroy them. Jesus said His burden is easy, and it is a good thing, because the ones we give ourselves rarely are. Good employees think that they have to do their best at work. And then the work expands, bringing discouragement or exhaustion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The true standard: good employees should do their best in the time they are given. Companies can not own slaves. If they are buying eight hours each day, give them an honest eight. Not ten. Have something else to do with those other hours, besides sleep: develop good hobbies, invest in family. Strong family relationships take time and can not be patched together as easily as work projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good employee who has things to look forward to after work will find that he remains a good employee and has a more fulfilling life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid burnout.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>True Adventure</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/true-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/true-adventure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“True adventurers have never been plentiful. They who are set down in print as such have been mostly business men with newly invented methods. They have been out after the things they wanted—golden fleeces, holy grails, lady loves, treasure, crowns and fame. The true adventurer goes forth aimless and uncalculating to meet and greet unknown fate. A fine example was the Prodigal Son&amp;ndash;when he started back home.” ~O. Henry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That paragraph from &lt;em&gt;The Green Door&lt;/em&gt; captures the essence of the Christian Adventure. Life is designed to require faith and the life of faith is an Adventure. For some years now I have felt called by God to go to China and learn the Chinese language and I think, “Won’t living in China be an adventure!” However, China is not the Christian Adventure. The Adventure is feeling and following the call of God when it looks impossible. It is desperately caring about the success of a situation when it is shadowed by certain failure in human terms. It is diving whole-heartedly into vague visions of the future when there is no earthly way that it will all work out. It is stepping into the Jordan River in hopes that God will dry it out. The Christian Adventure cannot be separated from prayer: kneeling in the darkness night after night and begging God for direction, begging Him for faith, begging for peace and confidence and contentment and joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Christian Adventure is being willing to calmly follow God into crushing trials because He has promised to never leave me and to work everything together for my good. It is passionately living under the will of Divine Benevolence. Do I have to go to China for adventure? No, I am living the Adventure now. And it just might be that the Adventure will lead me to China. God knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rest my unknown future on Christ who died for me. That is True Adventure and I am a True Adventurer!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fable of Simon McDarpet</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/the-fable-of-simon-mcdarpet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/the-fable-of-simon-mcdarpet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I give you the fable of Simon McDarpet,&lt;br /&gt;
A boy, it would seem, with a hatred for carpet;&lt;br /&gt;
And tables, of course, and most anything wooden&lt;br /&gt;
And things that get hurt when you act like you shouldn’t,&lt;br /&gt;
And all sorts of rugs, also windows and doors.&lt;br /&gt;
But your guess would be right if you singled out floors.&lt;br /&gt;
You’d be right on the money—the wad that was spent—&lt;br /&gt;
On repairing the issues he could have prevent-&lt;br /&gt;
ed because of the sloshing of liquids he did,&lt;br /&gt;
All because he refused to seal drinks with a lid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And don’t get me started on all of the chow&lt;br /&gt;
That was strewn down the hall in the wake of that cow.&lt;br /&gt;
Steaming heaps of lasagna and well-buttered biscuits,&lt;br /&gt;
Potatoes with herbs that were creamed with a wisk—it’s&lt;br /&gt;
A shame—and I know of the groans in my belly,&lt;br /&gt;
Surveying the wasted baked oatmeal and jelly.&lt;br /&gt;
However the groans that were felt in the gut&lt;br /&gt;
Of another man spying the path to the mutt&lt;br /&gt;
(Like a humanoid snail or a monstrous slug&lt;br /&gt;
Who was leaving a trail of wet smears on the rug);&lt;br /&gt;
These were groans that could make a man wither in fear&lt;br /&gt;
And concurrently make that same man shed a tear,&lt;br /&gt;
As poor Curtis would go fetch the tools of his trade,&lt;br /&gt;
For the treasure of kingdoms could scarcely have paid&lt;br /&gt;
For the hours he spent grimly cleaning the carpet&lt;br /&gt;
Of stains that were left by that Simon McDarpet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you’ll remember, dear cleanliness lover,&lt;br /&gt;
To never move food without using a cover.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday August 28, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/tuesday-august-28-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/tuesday-august-28-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everything that could go wrong at work went wrong. By about 4:00 it had all been tried, so things started going smooth again. And it happened on a day when I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to work.
Why do the days I&amp;rsquo;m excited about work end up being slow and the ones where I just want to do my stuff and leave end up going crazy? I guess I need the motivation more when the work is harder to find. And on crazy days it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how I feel: the job just has to get done. So while it seems backwards, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s right after all. Huh.
Well, I learned something new today, so I guess I can go to sleep now.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

