<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/tags/life-is-weird/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
    <copyright>© 2015 Ryan Clarke</copyright>
    <updated>Tue, 31 Jul 2007 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday July 31, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/tuesday-july-31-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/tuesday-july-31-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I was driving down the &amp;ldquo;Beeline&amp;rdquo; highway which forms the main drag of Payson and I came upon a semi parked directly across the entire five lanes of bi-direction traffic. So I stopped to see what was up. Also, he was blocking my path. But he was just backing into the little health food store. It was actually nerve-wracking because there was a crunched trunk licking my rear bumper. I mean, the guy had already proven he couldn&amp;rsquo;t drive, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want him reliving the moment on me. Not only was the front caved in, the whole truck was swayback, like a horse. It positively sagged in the middle. And then he passes me in the turn lane so that he could be second in line for the red light instead of back in, oh that&amp;rsquo;s right, still second place because I was turning into WAL*MART.
Did you know that the returns bin for candy at WAL*MART is labeled &amp;ldquo;Dept. 1.&amp;rdquo; Other than the obvious display of priorities, you have to wonder, why would you return candy? And what would you say? &amp;ldquo;But ma&amp;rsquo;am, I only used it once!&amp;rdquo;
The girl in front of me in line had a DVD: I asked her if it had a defective plot line. Turns out that she was there because the lines were shorter. Shorter in length certainly, but not quicker. There have a ritual ceremony they have you go through to return the whatever-it-is. And nobody has their receipts because they aren&amp;rsquo;t valuable for saving like old phone books or wheat pennies. I, of course, am different and conscientious. I have all my receipts stuffed into the center console of me car, except for the ones scattered around the dryer in little fuzzy balls. Come to think of it, even my console receipts are useless since they all turned very dark gray when I left my car parked in Phoenix on Light Broil for a week. But the principle still stands, whatever it was.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday July 7, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/saturday-july-7-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/saturday-july-7-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel excited because of my wound. But I&amp;rsquo;m not especially excited. Whenever I get really excited in an anticipatory way my lower gums get tingly and numb. And this sore on the inside of my lower lip is making my gums tingly and numb. So I keep wondering why I feel so vaguely excited&amp;hellip;
I went to the coffeeshop and read for a while. &amp;lsquo;Twas a good time: I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been in a while. And there was a guy trying to sing old-timey country, so that makes the experience even more colorful.
On a personal note, &amp;ldquo;The Lord of the Shoehorn&amp;rdquo; sounds like a good title.
&amp;ldquo;Enveloped in smoke and the burning of flames,
And the tumult of voices without any names,
Sitting high on a throne of white, porcelain mold
Reins the Lord of the Shoehorn, by whom men are soled.
And the traveler&amp;rsquo;s feet have been fated to stay
Weakly barefoot and feeble &amp;lsquo;til booted away.&amp;rdquo;
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday June 1, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/friday-june-1-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/friday-june-1-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night after work I went over to my coworker Joseph&amp;rsquo;s house and we ate pizza and watched Robots. Laughed our heads off. &amp;ldquo;Good luck with your dastardly plans.&amp;rdquo;
I also got a tax document in the mail saying I miscalculated my AZ tax return. They owe me \$203 dollars more than I thought. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how in the world I got that wrong. At least I was off in the right direction. Thank you, God, for the unexpected little boost! Because&amp;hellip;
Today the rent is due. Again. With all the regularity of those dashed lines on the road. And Cheese-its, which are always gone the day after you open the box.
On a slightly different note. It&amp;rsquo;s always fun it introduce myself to someone while I&amp;rsquo;m wearing my work uniform that has a name patch. &amp;ldquo;Hello, my name is&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; well, yesterday&amp;hellip; just a second&amp;hellip; *checks name patch*&amp;hellip; Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Ryan.&amp;rdquo;
I joined the choir. And everyone is still coming to church.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

