<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Verity on Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/tags/verity/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
    <copyright>© Ryan Clarke, 2014</copyright>
    <updated>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Last Visit to RCI</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/my-last-visit-to-rci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/my-last-visit-to-rci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m wandering around in the RCI. I never though this would happen again. Memories of past days are coming back and it&amp;rsquo;s been very nostalgic and fun. Volleyball in the ball room was just like I alway remember it, with the Team of Destiny chairs set up behind the nets. My old room 2628 is still set up the way JRod, Cameron and I left it, even though most other rooms are changed a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slept in Classroom 1 on the third floor. The only sign that Verity was even here are two office name tags that have never been removed from the wall. The lower dining room has now been set up like a living room with sofas and curtains: it&amp;rsquo;s very nice. I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in the lobby in front of the fireplace as I type this, in about the same spot that I received my Verity diploma about 2 and a half years ago. I can see the fishpond and the Mayor&amp;rsquo;s room where I taught Harmony to the &amp;lsquo;07ers and the front desk and the grand piano that Isaiah always used to play. I&amp;rsquo;m headed out now to go hear the huge organ at the First Presbyterian Church again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will never forget this place, or thing things I did here, or the people I knew here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday February 2, 2008</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/saturday-february-2-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/saturday-february-2-2008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am back at Verity now. I&amp;rsquo;ll be here for a while as guest lecturer and assistant to the curriculum developer. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, Verity is now in Indianapolis. So it&amp;rsquo;s odd going back to my school and finding it in an entirely different state. Still this is a nice place and the guys move into the new rooms today. I&amp;rsquo;m in with the staff guys and we get an entire 5 room suite. That&amp;rsquo;s nice. It should be a good run up here. I still haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten a glimpse of my sister - she was at the symphony till late last night.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday November 14, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/wednesday-november-14-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/wednesday-november-14-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m headed east! I&amp;rsquo;m spending a day at Verity before heading down to my good friend Bryce&amp;rsquo;s wedding where I&amp;rsquo;ll be the best man. Then I spend the whole following week and Thanksgiving with my family. This is going to be fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>