<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Religion on Ryan Clarke</title>
    <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/tags/religion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Religion on Ryan Clarke</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2017 Ryan Clarke</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//www.ryanclarke.net/tags/religion/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>As if I would trust my life upon a lie</title>
      <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/as-if-i-would-trust-my-life-upon-a-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/as-if-i-would-trust-my-life-upon-a-lie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Religious people are often called people of faith and participate in faith-based activities. In a culture that uses ‘faith’ so prominently and interchangeably with ‘religion’, I think many people are unaware of the Christian concept of faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I disagree. Hebrews 11:1 defines faith as “the substance of things hoped for, the evidence of things not seen.” Substance and evidence are not terms used to describe a mental handicap. If anything, they are meant to convey a confidence beyond any human will power. Mortimer J. Adler sums it up nicely when he writes, “You must always keep in mind that an article of faith is not something that the faithful ‘assume.’ Faith, for those who have it, is the most certain form of knowledge, not a tentative opinion.” A Christian’s faith transcends belief and rests in solid sureness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faith is often confused with belief. Merriam-Webster’s Dictionary gives one definition of faith as “firm belief in something for which there is no proof” and another as “sincerity of intentions.” While it includes other and better definitions, these two demonstrate the perceived weakness of faith in our society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a scientific and rational culture, proof and objectivity are regarded as prerequisites for trust in anything of importance. However, these same principles are deemed unimportant in matters of postmodern spirituality where everyone must find their own truth. Faith is simply a belief that the believer holds for comfort, tradition’s sake, or some moral expedient: anything but because it is really true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I disagree. Hebrews 11:1 defines faith as “the substance of things hoped for, the evidence of things not seen.” Substance and evidence are not terms used to describe a mental handicap. If anything, they are meant to convey a confidence beyond any human will power. Mortimer J. Adler sums it up nicely when he writes, “You must always keep in mind that an article of faith is not something that the faithful ‘assume.’ Faith, for those who have it, is the most certain form of knowledge, not a tentative opinion.” A Christian’s faith transcends belief and rests in solid sureness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, faith is described as the substance of a Christian’s hope: heaven. Popularly, hope is often used to express a wish or optimism, but a Christian’s hope is no mere whim if it has a present substance. Heaven and eternal life already exist and Christians currently possess them through the very faith in Christ which is the evidence of these things not seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christianity is not another wish upon a star. I do not stake my life upon Christ because it makes me feel good. I have faith is Christ because He’s true. Faith is my solid assurance in a definite guarantee. As if I would trust my life upon a lie.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Tis What Season...?</title>
      <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/tis-what-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/tis-what-season/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By the way, what season is it anyway? I was at Best Buy last night and I walked over to the table where they were selling the holiday gift cards. I say &amp;ldquo;holiday&amp;rdquo; with purpose. I&amp;rsquo;m not using it as a contraction of holy and day used for Christian celebrations, I&amp;rsquo;m using it as an all-purpose, non-religious term for the 25th of December, or more, Thanksgiving through New Year&amp;rsquo;s Day. (When was the last time you wished someone a happy holiday for July 4th? What about the Late Spring Holiday Season of Mother&amp;rsquo;s Day, Memorial Day, Father&amp;rsquo;s Day and Flag day?) So I&amp;rsquo;m standing at the gift card table and there are four different styles to suit everyone: Happy Kwanzaa, Happy Hanukkah, Love and Holiday (with a bride and a groom on it) and Giving Season with a gift. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t a &amp;ldquo;Christmas&amp;rdquo;, a manger, or a angel to be seen. Not even a serene looking female angel with long flaxen hair and a trumpet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I&amp;rsquo;m saying is that Christmas was a very big thing: God became man. It deserves a big celebration, and now it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even get a mention from corporate people who &amp;lsquo;know.&amp;rsquo; Sometimes it feels like they have taken the Christ out of Christmas and now they are destroying the last remnant of the X in Xmas. But I can still worship the newborn Christ, and that&amp;rsquo;s what I plan to do, whether it&amp;rsquo;s officially endorsed by Best Buy or not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth and Perception</title>
      <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/truth-and-perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/truth-and-perception/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it amazes me, the incredible arrogance of our intellect. As if our thoughts create reality. There is Truth and then there is Perception. Truth is what it is, but Perception is what we think Truth is. And we think that what we perceive Truth to be is the way Truth really is. Though Truth never changes, Perception does, and the vigilant will quickly realize how transient and impaired our finite grasp of real reality is within ourselves. And thus, before we can discover Truth, we must find unerring Perception. If our feeble attempts at Perception quickly become exposed as theory and opinion, then authority can only be found outside ourself in Knowledge, which is an understanding of Truth. We cannot generate Knowledge. Therefore, we cannot find Truth in its ultimate and purest state: Truth must be given to us. Who will give us Truth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look no farther that the Bible where we find Jesus proclaimed as The Word, the very embodiment of Knowledge. We also see Jesus defining Himself as The Truth. We ask ourself, is this a legitimate claim? The answer is a resounding affirmative since in Genesis we see Jesus making everything. God was, and then He created. God made reality and truth and therefore is intimately qualified to act as the supreme interpreter. Just as truth is unusable without being perceived and perception is dangerous unless it accurately reflects truth, so correct understanding is able to unlock the mysteries of life and allow us to live purposefully and meaningfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, we must endeavor to lay aside our own thinking and the philosophies of man which surround us and immerse ourselves in the knowing instructions of our Creator contained in the Bible. What a marvelous Book, with principles that even a child can live by and the answers to mysteries that have confounded geniuses for millennia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to believe something, I don&amp;rsquo;t need it to be easy or fair or even common-sensical, I just need it to be true, because my life depends on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

