<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paintball on Ryan Clarke</title>
    <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/tags/paintball/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paintball on Ryan Clarke</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2017 Ryan Clarke</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//www.ryanclarke.net/tags/paintball/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Monday September 17, 2007</title>
      <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/monday-september-17-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/monday-september-17-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw Herbie again and I still haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to take a picture. Yeah, he lives in my town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I played a little paintball today and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to report that my gun, with it&amp;rsquo;s new low-pressure mod (that I finally completed), performed admirably and I&amp;rsquo;m quite happy with the improvement. Not that you care, but you might be interested to know that I shot about 5 balls into the trunk of my car by mistake. Fortunately I hit some other paintball stuff in there so my fine gray carpet (I guess that what you call it) is not a mysteriously tie-dyed design like I had feared. &amp;ldquo;Fear&amp;rdquo; is probably a harsher term than necessary for my peculiar emotion: &amp;ldquo;surprised &amp;lsquo;huh&amp;rsquo;-ness&amp;rdquo; would be a more exact term. I&amp;rsquo;m just glad it didn&amp;rsquo;t happen to Herbie. Needless to say, since I was the winner of that little duel it had to carry me home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the final test for my evangelism training class. It was a very long handwritten test. By the end of it I was so cramped that my handwriting was changing styles faster than women&amp;rsquo;s clothing. It didn&amp;rsquo;t help that I keenly felt the pressure of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll wake up tomorrow and my cold will be gone. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t that be exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday August 26, 2007</title>
      <link>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/sunday-august-26-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ryanclarke.net/journal/sunday-august-26-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The choir men sang the special during church today. It was a killer-hard 3-part men&amp;rsquo;s piece. But after several weeks of practice we pretty much had it nailed and it came off well. We got tons of compliments and I even got 3 about my voice in particular. What can I say: I sing loud. So maybe my voice is improving into a viable, public-use instrument of praise.
We played paintball this afternoon. It&amp;rsquo;s always a blast. We played 4 games with 4 on 4 teams. Out of the 18 total eliminations made by both teams today, I shot 9 of them. I must have been on a roll. And I&amp;rsquo;m tired from running up and down the sides of the dirt gullys.
By the way, my listening on Wednesday night worked. The guy managed to talk himself into doing the right thing. He knew the truth and he was having trouble seeing it because of a few bad days: and I listen to him talk himself into the right. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how that works.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

