<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/tags/payson-az/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
    <copyright>© Ryan Clarke, 2014</copyright>
    <updated>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday December 6, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/thursday-december-6-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/thursday-december-6-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I made it back to Georgia about 24 hours ago. Sarah and I left Arizona a week ago Thursday and 2001 miles, 7 days, and 11 states later we made it home. Of course, you may be thinking that a week is a long time for such a drive and you&amp;rsquo;re right. We stopped for a day in Kansas for Mama Shoe&amp;rsquo;s memorial service and two days in Kentucky visiting the Reckner&amp;rsquo;s. So it was a leisurely trip. The last day was the most eventful. We were hardly 5 miles from the Reckner&amp;rsquo;s when the rear passenger tire totally disintegrated. We had to unload the entire trunk to get the jack and the spare out and that when I discovered that the included jack was totally useless for changing the rear tire. Fortunately Mr. Reckner had a bottle jack and was able to help me get changed to limp into town and get a new tire. It took a while so we didn&amp;rsquo;t head for home until mid-afternoon. But we&amp;rsquo;re back and it&amp;rsquo;s great to be with family again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the next step, whatever it is. All this has kept me crushingly busy so I&amp;rsquo;ll probably take a short breather and then start pursuing my future again with anticipation. There are these little dreams we all have, and maybe some of mine will start to come true. By &amp;ldquo;little&amp;rdquo; dreams, I mean those impossibly magnificient ideas that we harbor so close to our soul until they become a living part of us. Life isn&amp;rsquo;t always easy, but it&amp;rsquo;s terribly exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is My Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/this-is-my-thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/this-is-my-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been blessed with a good life. Throughout my journey, God has never ceased to shower all manner of sweet providence along my way. Many good things have happened to me that I have had no control over, from the dynamic family I was placed in to the amazing resilience of my fearfully made person.  And then, in love, God gently and surely called me to be His own and bought me with his blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My God has lead my steps, even when I was not consciously aware of His work. At other times when I cried for guidance and direction as I anxiously awaited looming deadlines and decisions, He has never failed to reveal His perfect and often unexpected will even if it may appear to be only at the last minute. Because of this long history of faithfulness to me, I can confidently approach the future with peace that it is in His hands. My present state of uncertainty has only worked to make me more excited about the possibilities ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My new adventure started on Monday, November the 12ᵗʰ.  I had just arrived home the weekend before from a week of work in Vancouver, BC, Canada manufacturing the last batch of MannaFlax with the supplies at our Surrey warehouse, and then packaging all the equipment and machinery for shipment back to Payson so we setup and continue operation in the states. This trip was very significant since it marked the end of the development cycle on the new health supplement we were making as we entered the production and commercial phase and started to sell product. I went to work on Monday expecting to start an endless (and hopefully increasing) cycle of making and selling. Instead, God had other plans. The Payson plant manager came to me and said that due to my efficient work effort in helping create MannaFlax and also some unrelated company financial difficulties I had worked myself out of a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expected to feel hurt or sad or disappointed, instead I felt happy and excited. When I started this job 17 months ago, I did it because God was clearly in it. Though I loved the job, and the interesting work, and fun coworkers, I always realized that the remote location was a very big drawback. Many times during my stay in Payson I’ve wanted to move so I could be closer to family and friends, but especially family. As hard as it was at times, I could never bring myself to leave because I was too comfortable to move and because I believed the Lord still wanted me here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For personal reasons, my week in Vancouver was very hard, a situation multiplied by the international factor prohibiting any phone calls to my family. I did a lot of thinking that week about packing up and moving on, even though I knew in my heart that I wouldn’t unless God clearly showed me I was to leave. Then unexpectedly on that Monday morning, God showed me the next step in His will.  And the event that I always viewed as a terrible thing made me smile because I knew my God cared for me and was making it easy for me to follow Him into the next adventure. It’s a funny thing about God, he likes to do things “backwards” but perfectly: first = last, humble = exalted, poor = rich, downsized = excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I finished up my work with the company and “put my affairs in order.” Then I flew out east for an absolute humdinger of a whirlwind tour with my family for Thanksgiving. Saying it was a great time would be an understatement. I am now back in Payson for a last few days packing up my few things in preparation to move home. My sister Sarah is flying out here tomorrow morning and we’ll be driving my Grandma Car back home. That should be a lot of fun. The church youth group is having a “We’re Mad at You for Leaving” party Wednesday night. Of all the things I’ll miss here in Arizona, by far the biggest will be the wonderful church family I have had the privilege of worshiping with this last year and some months. Ponderosa Baptist is a church where the majority of the people are doing ministry with the church is some way: it is a church that blows the 80-20 rule out of the water. It’s a beautiful thing to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now some people may think that this excursion to Payson has been a dead end that wasted many valuable months. In fact I am surprised that I don’t feel a little like that, but I find that I cannot be regretful in light of the many important things I’ve learned here. This post is already too long to list them all, and I’m sure I would forget some. I’m not sure if Payson, as a geographical location was so important, but the isolation from family and former friends, the unique mix of coworkers and new friends, and the special opportunities and challenges combined to make this “Payson Experience” a significant and necessary step in my personal growth. And let’s face it: Payson is a pretty nice place to live with one of the best climates I’ve ever experienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I move ahead. I must confess I really don’t know what I’ll be doing next, other than spending a nice December with my family. January is an open slate and rather than worry about it, I’ll trust God that He will fill in the details in His way in His time. He’s done it before and He can do it again. Frankly, I’m pretty excited to see what God does! This is my Thanksgiving, and God is the hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday October 19, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/friday-october-19-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/friday-october-19-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I cooked myself a nice, juicy, ribeye steak last night after marinating it for 3 days. And I had mashed potatoes. I just figured I&amp;rsquo;d let you all know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met the girl who&amp;rsquo;s dad painted the Herbie in my town. Her name was Emerald.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like Intel is going to phase out their single-core processors at the beginning of next year. Only dual- and quad-core will be available. And I doubt AMD will hold onto single-core much longer. It&amp;rsquo;s a good thing. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the consumer-priced quad-core 45nm PSUs that Intel has coming next February, although I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;ll get one. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely an interesting time on the PC hardware front as we&amp;rsquo;re finally starting to see the effects of Vista on hardware design. (That statement is not completely true, but that&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable consumer perspective on the trend.) Also, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu 7.10&lt;/a&gt; just came out yesterday. I&amp;rsquo;m downloading it today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1111 days bloggin for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday October 12, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/friday-october-12-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/friday-october-12-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Pastor Allen gave me a gift certificate to the Phoenix Symphony in appreciation for me filling in for him these last two weeks. I was quite surprised on top of happy. Of all the perfect gifts! So, now I just have to decide what I want to see&amp;hellip; and who to bring with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In just a few hours I head to the church to begin my long weekend with the youth. We drive through the night, spend Saturday at Magic Mountain riding coasters, Sunday morning at the beach freezing in the water, and then we drive and get back Sunday night. It&amp;rsquo;s 8 hours to Santa Barbara. And 8 hours back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday October 7, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/sunday-october-7-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/sunday-october-7-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My second weekend filling in for Pastor Allen with the youth is over. I have really enjoyed the opportunity to share more powerfully with the kids, but it&amp;rsquo;s tiring. God really blessed me and helped me. Last night at youth group I taught about anger and the good and bad kinds and how to correctly deal with it. This morning in Sunday School I taught the final lesson in a series called Totally Consumed about being an authentic worshiper. It was the lesson on revival and how revivals start with prayer and repentance in the lives of believers. &amp;ldquo;Revival starts with me.&amp;rdquo; Only as we show the world what a true believer looks like can they be attracted by our ambassadorship to Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another week of work comes ahead and then the youth trip to Magic Mountain to ride some roller coasters and listen to some good Christian youth speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday September 29, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/saturday-september-29-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/saturday-september-29-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We made enough money at the church yard sale to send all the youth students on the retreat to California! It was quite a success, but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty tired now. Okay, very tired. Filling in for Pastor Allen is not an easy job. And tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m teaching Sunday School for him too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also tomorrow I plan to swing by the 37th Annual Old-Time Fiddlers Contest. How could I miss something like that? It&amp;rsquo;s a busy weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday September 22, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/saturday-september-22-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/saturday-september-22-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I arrived back at work after lunch yesterday and found the street completely closed off by emergency vehicles. So the question is, what can possibly happen in Payson which will have 4 fire engines, 3 fire SUVs, 3 police cars, 2 police SUVs, and an ambulance to the scene in 10 minutes? I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you what, a camper trailer fire. Actually, the camper in the storage lot across from my work caught the camper next to it on fire and it burned up some too. The firemen were really excited about this one. I guess the last few weeks have been slow. And that&amp;rsquo;s the news from Payson where enough personnel to overthrow a small country arrive for a refrigerator fire.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monday September 17, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/monday-september-17-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/monday-september-17-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw Herbie again and I still haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to take a picture. Yeah, he lives in my town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I played a little paintball today and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to report that my gun, with it&amp;rsquo;s new low-pressure mod (that I finally completed), performed admirably and I&amp;rsquo;m quite happy with the improvement. Not that you care, but you might be interested to know that I shot about 5 balls into the trunk of my car by mistake. Fortunately I hit some other paintball stuff in there so my fine gray carpet (I guess that what you call it) is not a mysteriously tie-dyed design like I had feared. &amp;ldquo;Fear&amp;rdquo; is probably a harsher term than necessary for my peculiar emotion: &amp;ldquo;surprised &amp;lsquo;huh&amp;rsquo;-ness&amp;rdquo; would be a more exact term. I&amp;rsquo;m just glad it didn&amp;rsquo;t happen to Herbie. Needless to say, since I was the winner of that little duel it had to carry me home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the final test for my evangelism training class. It was a very long handwritten test. By the end of it I was so cramped that my handwriting was changing styles faster than women&amp;rsquo;s clothing. It didn&amp;rsquo;t help that I keenly felt the pressure of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll wake up tomorrow and my cold will be gone. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t that be exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost in the Superstition Mountains, Part 2</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/lost-in-the-superstition-mountains-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 02:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/lost-in-the-superstition-mountains-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I promised &lt;a href=&#34;/journal/lost-in-the-superstition-mountains&#34;&gt;previously&lt;/a&gt;, here are pictures from my adventure in the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went with some guys from church four-wheeling. We ended up getting lost and having to spend an extra day in the wild. I don&amp;rsquo;t have very many pictures yet, but here are a few. Here I am standing at the top of a hill we drove the trucks down. It was more like a cliff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/journal/like-abraham.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Like Abraham&#34; title=&#34;Like Abraham&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a sample of the roads we drove on. One truck got so stuck that we had to leave it. We took everything valuable, like a carburetor, out of it first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/journal/mountain-road.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mountain road&#34; title=&#34;Mountain Road&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll have better shots of the epic soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost in the Superstition Mountains</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/lost-in-the-superstition-mountains/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/lost-in-the-superstition-mountains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went out with some friends from church on Sunday and Monday. We went off-roading into the mountains east of Phoenix and camped the night. It was a rugged adventure. Unfortunately, the story doesn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense without images and my camera was one of the first things the wilderness claimed. Two other guys had cameras and took pictures and videos of most of the whole thing. So when I get a hold of some evidence, I&amp;rsquo;ll tell my once-in-a-lifetime (I hope!) tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then, travel in pairs - or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: &lt;a href=&#34;/journal/lost-in-the-superstition-mountains-part-2&#34;&gt;pictures here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday September 4, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/tuesday-september-4-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/tuesday-september-4-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We made it. I am back. I will say one thing about Arizona&amp;rsquo;s countryside: it&amp;rsquo;s very unforgiving.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday September 2, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/sunday-september-2-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/sunday-september-2-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spoke at men&amp;rsquo;s breakfast at church this morning. It went really well.
Tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m heading out with some guys deep into the mountains for an overnight camping trip. We&amp;rsquo;ll be back later on Monday.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday August 30, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/thursday-august-30-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/thursday-august-30-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s great to stand outside on a 93° day as the first, huge droplets come whistling down: the really gigantic drops that feel like a freezing poke every time you are hit. And then the temperature goes down 10° in 5 minutes. It&amp;rsquo;s a lovely event that happens most afternoons in August here. So&amp;hellip; same time, same place, tomorrow, eh?
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday August 28, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/tuesday-august-28-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/tuesday-august-28-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everything that could go wrong at work went wrong. By about 4:00 it had all been tried, so things started going smooth again. And it happened on a day when I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to work.
Why do the days I&amp;rsquo;m excited about work end up being slow and the ones where I just want to do my stuff and leave end up going crazy? I guess I need the motivation more when the work is harder to find. And on crazy days it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how I feel: the job just has to get done. So while it seems backwards, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s right after all. Huh.
Well, I learned something new today, so I guess I can go to sleep now.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday August 26, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/sunday-august-26-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/sunday-august-26-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The choir men sang the special during church today. It was a killer-hard 3-part men&amp;rsquo;s piece. But after several weeks of practice we pretty much had it nailed and it came off well. We got tons of compliments and I even got 3 about my voice in particular. What can I say: I sing loud. So maybe my voice is improving into a viable, public-use instrument of praise.
We played paintball this afternoon. It&amp;rsquo;s always a blast. We played 4 games with 4 on 4 teams. Out of the 18 total eliminations made by both teams today, I shot 9 of them. I must have been on a roll. And I&amp;rsquo;m tired from running up and down the sides of the dirt gullys.
By the way, my listening on Wednesday night worked. The guy managed to talk himself into doing the right thing. He knew the truth and he was having trouble seeing it because of a few bad days: and I listen to him talk himself into the right. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how that works.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

