<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Bible on Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/tags/bible/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
    <copyright>© Ryan Clarke, 2014</copyright>
    <updated>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>As if I would trust my life upon a lie</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/as-if-i-would-trust-my-life-upon-a-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/as-if-i-would-trust-my-life-upon-a-lie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Religious people are often called people of faith and participate in faith-based activities. In a culture that uses ‘faith’ so prominently and interchangeably with ‘religion’, I think many people are unaware of the Christian concept of faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I disagree. Hebrews 11:1 defines faith as “the substance of things hoped for, the evidence of things not seen.” Substance and evidence are not terms used to describe a mental handicap. If anything, they are meant to convey a confidence beyond any human will power. Mortimer J. Adler sums it up nicely when he writes, “You must always keep in mind that an article of faith is not something that the faithful ‘assume.’ Faith, for those who have it, is the most certain form of knowledge, not a tentative opinion.” A Christian’s faith transcends belief and rests in solid sureness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faith is often confused with belief. Merriam-Webster’s Dictionary gives one definition of faith as “firm belief in something for which there is no proof” and another as “sincerity of intentions.” While it includes other and better definitions, these two demonstrate the perceived weakness of faith in our society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a scientific and rational culture, proof and objectivity are regarded as prerequisites for trust in anything of importance. However, these same principles are deemed unimportant in matters of postmodern spirituality where everyone must find their own truth. Faith is simply a belief that the believer holds for comfort, tradition’s sake, or some moral expedient: anything but because it is really true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I disagree. Hebrews 11:1 defines faith as “the substance of things hoped for, the evidence of things not seen.” Substance and evidence are not terms used to describe a mental handicap. If anything, they are meant to convey a confidence beyond any human will power. Mortimer J. Adler sums it up nicely when he writes, “You must always keep in mind that an article of faith is not something that the faithful ‘assume.’ Faith, for those who have it, is the most certain form of knowledge, not a tentative opinion.” A Christian’s faith transcends belief and rests in solid sureness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, faith is described as the substance of a Christian’s hope: heaven. Popularly, hope is often used to express a wish or optimism, but a Christian’s hope is no mere whim if it has a present substance. Heaven and eternal life already exist and Christians currently possess them through the very faith in Christ which is the evidence of these things not seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christianity is not another wish upon a star. I do not stake my life upon Christ because it makes me feel good. I have faith is Christ because He’s true. Faith is my solid assurance in a definite guarantee. As if I would trust my life upon a lie.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth and Perception</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/truth-and-perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/truth-and-perception/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it amazes me, the incredible arrogance of our intellect. As if our thoughts create reality. There is Truth and then there is Perception. Truth is what it is, but Perception is what we think Truth is. And we think that what we perceive Truth to be is the way Truth really is. Though Truth never changes, Perception does, and the vigilant will quickly realize how transient and impaired our finite grasp of real reality is within ourselves. And thus, before we can discover Truth, we must find unerring Perception. If our feeble attempts at Perception quickly become exposed as theory and opinion, then authority can only be found outside ourself in Knowledge, which is an understanding of Truth. We cannot generate Knowledge. Therefore, we cannot find Truth in its ultimate and purest state: Truth must be given to us. Who will give us Truth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look no farther that the Bible where we find Jesus proclaimed as The Word, the very embodiment of Knowledge. We also see Jesus defining Himself as The Truth. We ask ourself, is this a legitimate claim? The answer is a resounding affirmative since in Genesis we see Jesus making everything. God was, and then He created. God made reality and truth and therefore is intimately qualified to act as the supreme interpreter. Just as truth is unusable without being perceived and perception is dangerous unless it accurately reflects truth, so correct understanding is able to unlock the mysteries of life and allow us to live purposefully and meaningfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, we must endeavor to lay aside our own thinking and the philosophies of man which surround us and immerse ourselves in the knowing instructions of our Creator contained in the Bible. What a marvelous Book, with principles that even a child can live by and the answers to mysteries that have confounded geniuses for millennia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to believe something, I don&amp;rsquo;t need it to be easy or fair or even common-sensical, I just need it to be true, because my life depends on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday October 7, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/sunday-october-7-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/sunday-october-7-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My second weekend filling in for Pastor Allen with the youth is over. I have really enjoyed the opportunity to share more powerfully with the kids, but it&amp;rsquo;s tiring. God really blessed me and helped me. Last night at youth group I taught about anger and the good and bad kinds and how to correctly deal with it. This morning in Sunday School I taught the final lesson in a series called Totally Consumed about being an authentic worshiper. It was the lesson on revival and how revivals start with prayer and repentance in the lives of believers. &amp;ldquo;Revival starts with me.&amp;rdquo; Only as we show the world what a true believer looks like can they be attracted by our ambassadorship to Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another week of work comes ahead and then the youth trip to Magic Mountain to ride some roller coasters and listen to some good Christian youth speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 37:3-7a</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/thursday-august-2-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/thursday-august-2-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once again I find myself reading Psalm 37.
&amp;ldquo;Trust in the LORD, and do good; so shalt thou dwell in the land, and verily thou shalt be fed. Delight thyself also in the LORD; and He shall give thee the desires of thine heart. Commit thy way unto the LORD; trust also in him; and He shall bring it to pass. And He shall bring forth thy righteousness as the light, and thy judgment as the noonday. Rest in the LORD, and wait patiently for Him.&amp;ldquo;  ~ Psalm 37:3-7a
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday July 24, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/tuesday-july-24-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/tuesday-july-24-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I get really mad today. Which is surprising since I&amp;rsquo;m a really easy going person and not much shakes me in that way. I can&amp;rsquo;t remember being mad for months, and then I&amp;rsquo;m fuming. It was kind of scary: I was seconds away from saying some imprudent things. As 1 Corinthians 10:12 says, &amp;ldquo;Wherefore let him that thinketh he standeth take heed lest he fall.&amp;rdquo; Fortunately I took heed and called my Mom where she was able to get my mind back on good things (Philippians 4:8).
It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that 1 Corinthians 10:12 is proceeded by some verses on the Israelites in the desert in verses 1-11. &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; brethren, I would not that ye should be ignorant, how that all our fathers were under the cloud, and all passed through the sea; and were all baptized unto Moses in the cloud and in the sea; and did eat the same spiritual meat; and did drink the same spiritual drink: for the drank of that spiritual Rock that followed them: and that Rock was Christ. But with many of them God was not pleased: for they were overthrown in the wilderness. &amp;hellip; Neither be ye idolaters &amp;hellip; commit fornication &amp;hellip; tempt Christ &amp;hellip; murmur &amp;hellip; as some of them &amp;hellip; and were destroyed of the destroyer. Now these things happened unto them for ensamples: and they are written for our admonition, upon whom the ends of the world are come.&amp;rdquo; Then finally, &amp;ldquo;Wherefore let him that thinketh he standeth take heed lest he fall.&amp;rdquo;
And it&amp;rsquo;s so easy to get caught up in Christless actions and attitudes. Take heed. I got a big warning today. Thank God for Mom!
Ryan
By the way, my xanga is now 2¹° days old.
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday July 12, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/thursday-july-12-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/thursday-july-12-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My upgraded computer is running fine. I put in a new CPU and some more RAM today. Ah, I like tweaking it to work better when I have time. My current setup is listed below:
Name: WHISTLE
AMD Athlon 64 X2 5600+ at 2.8GHz
4MB SDRAM DRR2 800 (PC2 6400)
2x nVidia GeForce 7600GT in SLI
ASUS M2N-SLI Deluxe with nForce 570 SLI MCP
2x 320GB Seagate Barracuda 7200RPM SATA 3.0GB/s
Dual-booting XP Home and Vista Ultimate
CD/DVD±RW
22&amp;rdquo; Widescreen and 19&amp;rdquo; Standard LCD monitors
I use this powerful machine to post the verse of the day on xanga:
&amp;ldquo;The fruit of the righteous is a tree of life, and he who is wise wins souls.&amp;rdquo;
       ~ Proverbs 11:30
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 40:9-10</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/psalm-40-9-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/psalm-40-9-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have proclaimed glad tidings of righteousness in the great congregation; Behold, I will not restrain my lips, O Lord, Thou knowest. I have not hidden Thy righteousness within my heart; I have spoken of Thy faithfulness and Thy salvation; I have not concealed Thy lovingkindness and Thy truth from the great congregation.&amp;rdquo;
     ~ Psalm 40:9-10
Most scholars agree (okay, I only checked with Spurgeon&amp;rsquo;s Treasury of Psalms) that this passage, and much of the entire Psalm, is written about Christ and His unwavering proclamation of the Kingdom of God&amp;rsquo;s imminence during His years of ministry. When I read this passage this morning my first thought was on the evangelism training I&amp;rsquo;m going through with my church. When I insert my self in there, and switch all &amp;ldquo;the great congregations&amp;rdquo; out for the &amp;ldquo;the world&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;lost and helpless people.&amp;rdquo;
May I be worthy of the task.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 33:18-22</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/psalm-33-18-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/psalm-33-18-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Behold, the eye of the Lord is on those who fear Him,
On those who hope for His lovingkindness,
To deliver their soul from death,
And to keep them alive in famine.
Our soul waits for the Lord;
He is our help and our shield.
For our heart rejoices in Him,
Because we trust in His holy name.
Let Thy lovingkindness, O Lord, be upon us,
According as we have hoped in Thee.
   ~   Psalm 33:18-22
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday May 15, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/tuesday-may-15-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/tuesday-may-15-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My little children, I am writing these things to you that you may not sin.&amp;rdquo; 1 John 2:1a
It&amp;rsquo;s true. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying in 1 John sin has been less attractive to me. I am sinning less. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing. Of course, John is a realist and knows we&amp;rsquo;re still going to sin. So he finishes that verse: &amp;ldquo;And if anyone sins, we have an Advocate with the Father, Jesus Christ the righteous.&amp;rdquo; 1 John 2:1b
If you read 1 John you will sin less: it&amp;rsquo;s the point of the book. And it does it by making us realize God&amp;rsquo;s love, and letting us love Him back (1 John 4:10, 19). Listen to this familiar passage that brought me to grateful tears last night:
&amp;ldquo;See how great a love the Father has bestowed upon us, that we should be called children of God: and such we are. For this reason the world does not know us, because it does not know Him. Beloved, now we are children of God, and it has not appeared yet what we shall be. We know that, when He appears, we shall be like Him, because we shall see Him as He is. And everyone who has this hope fixed on Him purifies himself, just as He is pure. Do not marvel if the world hates you. We know that we have passed out of death into life, because we love the brethren. He who does not love abides in death.&amp;rdquo; 1 John 3:1-3, 13-14)
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monday May 14, 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/monday-may-14-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://ryanclarke.github.io/journal/monday-may-14-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading 1 John a lot lately. It&amp;rsquo;s a small book so I&amp;rsquo;ve read chapters several times. John&amp;rsquo;s writing makes him sound like the nicest man ever. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how kind the words sound, even though so many of them are convicting and speak strongly against sin in a Christian&amp;rsquo;s life. That&amp;rsquo;s how true Christianity should be, truthful but loving. Read 1 John: it&amp;rsquo;s like getting a hug.
This has been Ryan, promoting a &amp;lsquo;little book&amp;rsquo; of the Bible.
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>