<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/tags/god-is-good/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
    <copyright>© 2015 Ryan Clarke</copyright>
    <updated>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monday August 20, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/monday-august-20-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/monday-august-20-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really tired tonight. It must have been my amazingly full weekend: parade, rodeo, teaching teen Sunday school, paintball, evangelism training, etc.
I better go to bed early before I lose it. I am prone to trust Christ less when I&amp;rsquo;m tired; and without Christ, things of life are very dismal indeed. Although with Christ, life can be joy and peace in the midst of any circumstances. So with that, I head to bed.
God is too good to me.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 37:3-7a</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/thursday-august-2-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/thursday-august-2-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once again I find myself reading Psalm 37.
&amp;ldquo;Trust in the LORD, and do good; so shalt thou dwell in the land, and verily thou shalt be fed. Delight thyself also in the LORD; and He shall give thee the desires of thine heart. Commit thy way unto the LORD; trust also in him; and He shall bring it to pass. And He shall bring forth thy righteousness as the light, and thy judgment as the noonday. Rest in the LORD, and wait patiently for Him.&amp;ldquo;  ~ Psalm 37:3-7a
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday June 6, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/wednesday-june-6-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/wednesday-june-6-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And so, I finished my first year of work. I should have been a happy day as not only was it a big milestone but I was covered in sugar almost the entire afternoon. But for some reason I had one of my lowest days in months. I was overwhelmed with a sense of futility (I hate it when that happens). Mom says it&amp;rsquo;s good though, because it proves that I&amp;rsquo;m real. Haha, I had to laugh. I guess I am happy almost all the time, and I don&amp;rsquo;t let bad situations steal my joy. But occasionally that little unrest in my soul that pushes me to dream bigger things breaks loose and points a haughty finger at the pleasant niche I&amp;rsquo;ve carved alone here in Arizona. And I wish for more.
I feel better now because I&amp;rsquo;m realizing I&amp;rsquo;ve done more this last year than go to work 244 days. I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, I&amp;rsquo;ve matured, and I&amp;rsquo;ve proven myself, in some small way, to myself. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m closer to the goal.
On a personal note: I saw myself in the mirror this morning. Again.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday May 31, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/thursday-may-31-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Clarke</author>
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/thursday-may-31-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m back in the normal flow of things. I&amp;rsquo;ve recovered lost sleep from this last weekend.
God is good to me.
And now I&amp;rsquo;m off to get more sleep.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

