<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Uncategorized on Ryan Clarke </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/categories/uncategorized/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Sun, 10 Jun 2007 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday June 10, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/sunday-june-10-2007</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/sunday-june-10-2007</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Though not entirely new, this story is fairly recent.
So the UK, not content with having 4.2 million closed circuit cameras filming the normal citizen an average 300 times a day, is upping the crime fighting ploy. They have added speakers to the cameras so that monitoring authorities can scold citizens for &amp;ldquo;anti-social behavior,&amp;rdquo; like littering. Of course it&amp;rsquo;s not all bad, the chiding voices are recordings of friendly children, like that makes me feel better: getting blasted by a 6-year-old. And if getting anonymously reprimanded in public was not enough, they are planning to equip the them with microphones (to detect &amp;ldquo;aggresive tones&amp;rdquo; by pitch, volume, and speed) and lip-reading software (to search for “key words and sentences”) to automatically notify authorities of criminal intent. It gets better, because they are also deploying fully-outfitted, 2-foot, stealth helicopter drones which, through preprogrammed flight plans or remote control, are are able to track down suspicious individuals.
And finally, if you&amp;rsquo;re planning on going to England, go soon. They are preparing to install x-ray to the cameras also. This will help in the dark, and with weapons and explosives detection. Oh, and everyone shows up on the screen naked. We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised, they&amp;rsquo;ve already got cameras in the bathrooms (I can&amp;rsquo;t believe 45% of Britons approved the decision).
All this in spite of a British Government study that found that lighting was more effective in lowering crime than cameras. I say, put in some lights, oh, and return their guns. But please, don&amp;rsquo;t remove my clothes and then yell at me!
The Raw Story 5-30-07 article: &lt;a href=&#34;http://rawstory.com/news/2007/Orwell_rolls_in_his_grave_0530.html&#34;&gt;Orwell rolls in his grave&lt;/a&gt;
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday June 8, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/friday-june-8-2007</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/friday-june-8-2007</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to become a celebrity. Does anyone know some good paparazzi in the Greater Payson Metropolitan Area *cough*? Yes, I&amp;rsquo;ve always dreamed of being draped across the checkout aisle in Wal*Mart beneath slanderous headlines.
I&amp;rsquo;m just not sure about the whole adopting native children thing: I&amp;rsquo;d rather have my own.
Now to figure out what to be a celebrity for. I can&amp;rsquo;t be famous for being famous or rich, because I&amp;rsquo;m neither. Yet. That leave me with one alternative: &amp;lsquo;lack of any distinguishable talent.&amp;rsquo; I&amp;rsquo;ll join the hordes of people who&amp;rsquo;s only claim to fame is being in every issue of The Irrational Admirer since distant memory. Or I could try being arrested and released and rejailed. But face it, a celebrity has to really want it in order to be actually locked up, most just settle for endless trips to rehab.
You may all take an unflattering picture now.
Ryan
in backlash at the entertainment [sic: irrelevancy] saturated news
**edited to include Emily&amp;rsquo;s brilliant observation**
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday June 5, 2007</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/tuesday-june-5-2007</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ryanclarke.net/journal/tuesday-june-5-2007</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What if you woke up one morning and you couldn&amp;rsquo;t see yourself in a mirror. You couldn&amp;rsquo;t even see yourself in your cereal spoon. That would be weird.
Ryan
Originally posted at classicalRyan.xanga.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>